
import { MCQ } from '@/lib/types';

export const chapters = [
  "Seert-un-Nabi (Universally desired personality traits)",
  "Eid ul Fitr (Festival and Cultural Events)",
  "The Lake Isle of Innisfree (Nature)",
  "Major Shabbir Sharif Shaheed (Role Models)",
  "Harmony in Society (Peaceful Co-existence / Peace Education)",
  "First Aid Saves Life (Crisis Management and Risk Reduction)",
  "Corruption (Avoiding Social Evils)",
  "Importance of Science & Technology (Science and Technology)",
  "Overpopulation - a Dilemma (Population Education)",
  "Education is my Right (Gender Equality and Equity)",
  "A Poem by a Soldier (Patriotism / National Pride)",
  "Good Citizen (Participatory Citizenship)",
];

export const mcqs: Record<string, MCQ[]> = {
  "Seert-un-Nabi (Universally desired personality traits)": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What is the full Arabic phrase mentioned at the beginning of the English Grade 6 book?", "options": ["In the Name of God, the Almighty", "In the Name of Allah, the Most Compassionate, the Most Merciful", "Praise be to Allah", "God is Great"], "correctAnswer": "In the Name of Allah, the Most Compassionate, the Most Merciful" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "Which personality traits are highlighted in the context of Rasulullah (SAW)?", "options": ["Honesty and generosity", "Honesty and intelligence", "Honesty and steadfastness", "Honesty and trustworthiness"], "correctAnswer": "Honesty and trustworthiness" },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "What title was Rasulullah (SAW) known by due to his integrity and trustworthiness?", "options": ["Al-Sadiq", "Al-Ameen", "Al-Sadiq and Al-Ameen", "Al-Kareem"], "correctAnswer": "Al-Sadiq and Al-Ameen" },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "Who did Rasulullah (SAW) write a letter to, inviting him to embrace Islam?", "options": ["Emperor Byzamtium", "Emperor Heraclius", "Abu Sufyan", "Both a and b"], "correctAnswer": "Emperor Heraclius" },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "Who verified Rasulullah's (SAW) honesty and trustworthiness to Emperor Heraclius?", "options": ["Abu Talib", "Abu Sufyan", "Hazrat Khadija", "Bani Makhzum"], "correctAnswer": "Abu Sufyan" },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "How did Rasulullah (SAW) treat his household and others?", "options": ["With love and compassion", "With strictness", "With indifference", "With favoritism"], "correctAnswer": "With love and compassion" },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "What is mentioned as a noble and magnificent characteristic of Hazrat Muhammad (SAW)?", "options": ["Courage", "Justice", "Generosity", "Wisdom"], "correctAnswer": "Justice" },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "From which tribe did a woman commit theft and was brought before Rasulullah (SAW)?", "options": ["Quraish", "Bani Makhzum", "Hashim", "Adnan"], "correctAnswer": "Bani Makhzum" },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "Why did Rasulullah (SAW) refuse to forgive the woman who committed theft?", "options": ["To set an example", "Because of her tribe's status", "To uphold justice", "He disliked her"], "correctAnswer": "To uphold justice" },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "What lesson can we learn from the life of Rasulullah (SAW)?", "options": ["How to achieve wealth", "How to conduct ourselves honorably", "How to win battles", "How to gain power"], "correctAnswer": "How to conduct ourselves honorably" },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "In the dialogue, what does Dawood want to buy?", "options": ["New clothes", "A new bag", "Fruits", "Groceries"], "correctAnswer": "Groceries" },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "Who helps Dawood in the market?", "options": ["Old Man", "Allah", "Dawod's family", "Shopkeeper"], "correctAnswer": "Old Man" },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "What is the meaning of the word 'reliability'?", "options": ["consistency", "trustworthiness", "honesty", "firmness"], "correctAnswer": "trustworthiness" },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "What does 'summoned' mean?", "options": ["asked", "called", "ordered", "requested"], "correctAnswer": "called" },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "The word 'cloak' refers to a:", "options": ["coat", "shawl", "scarf", "blanket"], "correctAnswer": "coat" },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'staunch'?", "options": ["weak", "firmest", "flexible", "unreliable"], "correctAnswer": "firmest" },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "Which of the following is an example of a compound word?", "options": ["backbite", "backlight", "backflip", "backpack"], "correctAnswer": "backpack" },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "Combine 'snow' and 'flake' to form a compound word:", "options": ["snowfall", "snowflake", "snowstorm", "snowdrop"], "correctAnswer": "snowflake" },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "What is the compound word formed from 'copy' and 'right'?", "options": ["copycat", "copyright", "copybook", "copier"], "correctAnswer": "copyright" },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "Which of these is a homophone for 'weather'?", "options": ["whether", "wether", "wetter", "wither"], "correctAnswer": "whether" },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "Choose the correct homophone for 'scene':", "options": ["seen", "sing", "sane", "sun"], "correctAnswer": "seen" },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "What is the homophone for 'hair'?", "options": ["hare", "hear", "here", "heir"], "correctAnswer": "hare" },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "Which word is a homophone for 'herd'?", "options": ["hard", "heard", "hide", "hurt"], "correctAnswer": "heard" },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "Select the correct homophone to complete the sentence: 'Please _____ the cheese for me.'", "options": ["great", "grate", "greet", "grit"], "correctAnswer": "grate" },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "Choose the correct homophone to complete the sentence: 'Who ate my pancakes?'", "options": ["eight", "ait", "eat", "out"], "correctAnswer": "eight" },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "A noun is a naming word. It can be the name of a:", "options": ["thing, person, place, object (animate or inanimate) or feeling", "action, state, or occurrence", "quality, state, or abstract idea", "relation of place, time, circumstance, manner, or cause"], "correctAnswer": "thing, person, place, object (animate or inanimate) or feeling" },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "Which of the following is an example of a Common Noun?", "options": ["Lahore", "Ahmed", "teacher", "Titanic"], "correctAnswer": "teacher" },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "'Allama Iqbal' is an example of what type of noun?", "options": ["Common Noun", "Proper Noun", "Collective Noun", "Abstract Noun"], "correctAnswer": "Proper Noun" },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "Which of these is a Collective Noun?", "options": ["tiger", "house", "army", "teacher"], "correctAnswer": "army" },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "'Kindness' is an example of what type of noun?", "options": ["Common Noun", "Proper Noun", "Concrete Noun", "Abstract Noun"], "correctAnswer": "Abstract Noun" },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "Concrete nouns can be detected and felt with our:", "options": ["five senses", "thoughts", "emotions", "imagination"], "correctAnswer": "five senses" },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "In the sentence 'Our teacher gives us many tasks,' what is the post modifier?", "options": ["Our", "teacher", "many", "tasks"], "correctAnswer": "many" },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "In 'The man in the blue shirt is my neighbour,' which phrase is the post modifier?", "options": ["The man", "in the blue shirt", "is my neighbour", "my neighbour"], "correctAnswer": "in the blue shirt" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "Which of these nouns is always spoken as a plural noun, even if it refers to a single item?", "options": ["news", "scissors", "pants", "all of the above"], "correctAnswer": "all of the above" },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "What is the definition of a sentence?", "options": ["A group of words", "A complete unit of thought", "A collection of verbs", "A phrase with meaning"], "correctAnswer": "A complete unit of thought" },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "An intransitive verb needs what to complete its meaning?", "options": ["an object", "a subject", "no objects", "a direct object"], "correctAnswer": "no objects" },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "In a Subject Verb Object (SVO) pattern, what comes after the subject?", "options": ["an adjective", "a transitive verb", "an intransitive verb", "a noun"], "correctAnswer": "a transitive verb" },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "Which sentence uses correct capitalization?", "options": ["sana lives in dubai.", "Sana lives in dubai.", "Sana Lives In Dubai.", "sana lives In Dubai."], "correctAnswer": "Sana lives in dubai." },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "What is the main idea of a paragraph called?", "options": ["Supporting sentence", "Topic sentence", "Concluding sentence", "Detail sentence"], "correctAnswer": "Topic sentence" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "Sentences that support the main idea of a paragraph are called:", "options": ["Topic sentences", "Introductory sentences", "Supporting sentences", "Concluding sentences"], "correctAnswer": "Supporting sentences" },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "Where is the first word of a sentence capitalized?", "options": ["Only at the beginning of a paragraph", "Always", "Only for questions", "Rarely"], "correctAnswer": "Always" },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "What are the initials of people's first and last names capitalized?", "options": ["Sometimes", "Never", "Always", "Only if they are famous"], "correctAnswer": "Always" },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "In a quotation, the first word is capitalized.", "options": ["True", "False", "Sometimes", "Only for short quotations"], "correctAnswer": "True" },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "Which punctuation mark is used at the end of a declarative sentence?", "options": ["Question mark", "Exclamation mark", "Full stop", "Comma"], "correctAnswer": "Full stop" },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "What is the purpose of 'Writing Skill' in Unit 1?", "options": ["To practice dictation", "To fill in the blanks", "To write a mind map about Hazrat Muhammad (SAW)", "To memorize definitions"], "correctAnswer": "To write a mind map about Hazrat Muhammad (SAW)" },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "Which aspect of Hazrat Muhammad's (SAW) life is NOT a heading in the mind map example?", "options": ["Qualities", "Career", "Place of birth", "Childhood friends"], "correctAnswer": "Childhood friends" },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "How many lines should a paragraph about a proud moment in life be?", "options": ["5-7 lines", "8-10 lines", "9-10 lines", "11-12 lines"], "correctAnswer": "9-10 lines" },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "What should you do to make a paragraph interesting?", "options": ["Punctuate and capitalize the text properly", "Use long sentences", "Add irrelevant details", "Use only simple words"], "correctAnswer": "Punctuate and capitalize the text properly" },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "What is the purpose of the 'Role play' activity in Unit 1?", "options": ["To practice writing skills", "To make polite requests and use non-verbal cues", "To answer comprehension questions", "To learn new vocabulary"], "correctAnswer": "To make polite requests and use non-verbal cues" },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "The English Grade 6 textbook is based on:", "options": ["Provincial Curriculum 2022", "Single National Curriculum 2022", "International Curriculum 2022", "Punjab Curriculum 2022"], "correctAnswer": "Single National Curriculum 2022" }
  ],
  "Eid ul Fitr (Festival and Cultural Events)": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "Eid-ul-Fitr is a significant religious and cultural festival for:", "options": ["Christians", "Muslims", "Hindus", "Buddhists"], "correctAnswer": "Muslims" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "Eid-ul-Fitr marks the end of which month?", "options": ["Shawwal", "Ramadan", "Muharram", "Rajab"], "correctAnswer": "Ramadan" },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "On which day of the Islamic calendar does Eid-ul-Fitr fall?", "options": ["1st of Ramadan", "10th of Shawwal", "1st of Shawwal", "27th of Ramadan"], "correctAnswer": "1st of Shawwal" },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "What is the night before Eid celebrations known as?", "options": ["Lailatul Qadr", "Chaand Raat", "Eid Night", "Festive Night"], "correctAnswer": "Chaand Raat" },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "What do females often apply on their hands as part of Eid preparations?", "options": ["Nail polish", "Mehndi", "Henna", "Both b and c"], "correctAnswer": "Both b and c" },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "What is the special prayer offered on Eid day called?", "options": ["Salat ul Isha", "Salat ul Maghrib", "Salat ul Eid", "Salat ul Fajr"], "correctAnswer": "Salat ul Eid" },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "Where do Muslim men and children gather to offer Eid prayers?", "options": ["At home", "In a mosque or open place", "In a community hall", "At a friend's house"], "correctAnswer": "In a mosque or open place" },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "What is a common tradition regarding clothing on Eid?", "options": ["Wearing old clothes", "Wearing new clothes or clean old ones", "Wearing only white clothes", "Wearing traditional clothes only"], "correctAnswer": "Wearing new clothes or clean old ones" },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "What kind of special desserts are enjoyed on Eid?", "options": ["Vermicelli and milk", "Kheer", "Sweet made with vermicelli and milk, kheer, local desserts", "Fruit salad"], "correctAnswer": "Sweet made with vermicelli and milk, kheer, local desserts" },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "In the dialogue, what did Usman bring from the market for Eid day?", "options": ["Fruits", "Vegetables", "All the things from the shopping list", "Sweets"], "correctAnswer": "All the things from the shopping list" },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "What is the main ingredient for Kheer, mentioned in the dialogue?", "options": ["Sugar", "Milk and rice", "Dry fruits", "Vermicelli"], "correctAnswer": "Milk and rice" },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "Why do the characters in the dialogue decide to avoid 'junk food' on Eid?", "options": ["It's expensive", "It causes weight gain and stomach problems", "They don't like it", "It's not traditional"], "correctAnswer": "It causes weight gain and stomach problems" },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "Homographs are words that:", "options": ["have the same spelling and meaning but different pronunciation.", "have different spelling and pronunciation but same meaning.", "have the same spelling but different meanings and sometimes different pronunciation.", "have the same meaning and pronunciation but different spelling."], "correctAnswer": "have the same spelling but different meanings and sometimes different pronunciation." },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "What does 'resign' (verb) mean as a homograph?", "options": ["to quit", "to sign again", "to give up", "to finish"], "correctAnswer": "to quit" },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "What does 'wind' (verb) mean as a homograph?", "options": ["to finish", "air", "to blow", "to turn"], "correctAnswer": "to turn" },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "In the sentence, 'I am going to lead this team,' what is the meaning of 'lead'?", "options": ["to head", "a type of matter", "to follow", "to push"], "correctAnswer": "to head" },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "Which of the following words is a homograph?", "options": ["happy", "run", "bass", "tree"], "correctAnswer": "bass" },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'minute' as a homograph, distinct from a unit of time?", "options": ["very small", "a short time", "to write down", "to record"], "correctAnswer": "very small" },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "The word 'tear' can mean:", "options": ["a rip", "fluid from the eye", "both a and b", "a type of tree"], "correctAnswer": "both a and b" },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "What are the two common meanings of 'watch' as a homograph?", "options": ["a timepiece and to observe", "to sing and to dance", "a game and a tool", "to cook and to eat"], "correctAnswer": "a timepiece and to observe" },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "A gender that represents males or refers to objects classified as male is:", "options": ["Feminine Gender", "Masculine Gender", "Neuter Gender", "Common Gender"], "correctAnswer": "Masculine Gender" },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "'Cow' is an example of which gender noun?", "options": ["Masculine Gender", "Feminine Gender", "Neuter Gender", "Common Gender"], "correctAnswer": "Feminine Gender" },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "Which of the following is an example of a Common Gender noun?", "options": ["bull", "grandmother", "teacher", "witch"], "correctAnswer": "teacher" },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "'Rope' is an example of which gender noun?", "options": ["Masculine Gender", "Feminine Gender", "Neuter Gender", "Common Gender"], "correctAnswer": "Neuter Gender" },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "Demonstrative pronouns are used to:", "options": ["ask questions", "show or point out something", "indicate possession", "replace nouns"], "correctAnswer": "show or point out something" },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "Which of these is a singular demonstrative pronoun used for something close to the speaker?", "options": ["Those", "These", "This", "That"], "correctAnswer": "This" },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "In the sentence 'Look at this!', 'this' is a:", "options": ["Personal pronoun", "Interrogative pronoun", "Demonstrative pronoun", "Relative pronoun"], "correctAnswer": "Demonstrative pronoun" },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "'They' in 'They are many flowers. Do you like these?' is a:", "options": ["Singular demonstrative pronoun", "Plural demonstrative pronoun", "Singular personal pronoun", "Plural personal pronoun"], "correctAnswer": "Plural personal pronoun" },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "What is the structure of a Subject-verb-adjective (SVA) pattern sentence?", "options": ["Subject + verb + noun", "Subject + verb + adjective", "Subject + adjective + verb", "Verb + subject + adjective"], "correctAnswer": "Subject + verb + adjective" },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "In 'He seems happy', what is the verb?", "options": ["He", "seems", "happy", "seems happy"], "correctAnswer": "seems" },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "The simple present tense is used when an action takes place:", "options": ["in the past", "in the future", "in the present time, or when it happens regularly", "continuously"], "correctAnswer": "in the present time, or when it happens regularly" },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "What is the affirmative sentence structure for Simple Present Tense?", "options": ["Subject + verb (past form) + object.", "Subject + verb (present form) + s/es + object.", "Subject + will/shall + verb (present form) + object.", "Subject + is/am/are + verb-ing + object."], "correctAnswer": "Subject + verb (present form) + s/es + object." },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "Choose the correct option: 'I play / plays football every Saturday.'", "options": ["play", "plays", "played", "playing"], "correctAnswer": "play" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "Choose the correct option: 'Do / Does they listen to rap music?'", "options": ["Do", "Does", "Did", "Will"], "correctAnswer": "Do" },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "The simple past tense tells us about actions that took place in:", "options": ["the present time", "the future", "a time period before the present time", "continuous time"], "correctAnswer": "a time period before the present time" },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "What is the negative sentence structure for Simple Past Tense?", "options": ["Subject + do/does + not + verb (present form) + object.", "Subject + did + not + verb (present form) + object.", "Subject + will/shall + not + verb (present form) + object.", "Subject + is/am/are + not + verb-ing + object."], "correctAnswer": "Subject + did + not + verb (present form) + object." },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "Complete the sentence using the simple past tense: 'The show ______ at 10:30.'", "options": ["begin", "begins", "began", "beginning"], "correctAnswer": "began" },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "Complete the sentence using the simple past tense: 'Amna ______ from Multan.'", "options": ["come", "comes", "came", "coming"], "correctAnswer": "came" },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "The simple future tense is used to talk about things that haven't happened:", "options": ["yet", "yesterday", "always", "now"], "correctAnswer": "yet" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "What is the interrogative sentence structure for Simple Future Tense?", "options": ["Subject + will/shall + verb (present form) + object.", "Will/Shall + subject + verb (present form) + object?", "Subject + will/shall + not + verb (present form) + object.", "Do/Does + subject + verb (present form) + object?"], "correctAnswer": "Will/Shall + subject + verb (present form) + object?" },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "Fill in the blank: 'I _______ wear a sweater next week.'", "options": ["will", "shall", "am", "have"], "correctAnswer": "shall" },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "Fill in the blank: 'When ______ you go to Canada again?'", "options": ["will", "shall", "are", "do"], "correctAnswer": "will" },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'will' and 'shall' in the context of the future tense?", "options": ["Past verbs", "Present verbs", "Auxiliary verbs", "Connecting words"], "correctAnswer": "Auxiliary verbs" },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "What is an exclamation mark (!) used to show?", "options": ["Questions or uncertainty", "Strong emotions or feelings", "Pauses in a sentence", "Possession"], "correctAnswer": "Strong emotions or feelings" },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "What is the primary purpose of writing a narrative paragraph?", "options": ["To argue a point", "To inform the reader", "To tell a story or describe an event", "To persuade the reader"], "correctAnswer": "To tell a story or describe an event" },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "Which of the following is NOT a guideline for writing a narrative?", "options": ["Write the heading on top of the page", "Organize the events in right order", "Use present tense only", "Use appropriate vocabulary to show characters' feelings"], "correctAnswer": "Use present tense only" },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "What should the writing (narrative) contain to be complete?", "options": ["All facts, heading, characters, setting, key details, main idea and ending", "Only the main idea", "Just characters and setting", "Only the ending"], "correctAnswer": "All facts, heading, characters, setting, key details, main idea and ending" },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "What is the final step in reviewing a narrative draft?", "options": ["Check spelling", "Proofread for errors and necessary corrections", "Rewrite the introduction", "Add more details"], "correctAnswer": "Proofread for errors and necessary corrections" },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "What kind of writing is exemplified by the account of Independence Day celebrations?", "options": ["Expository", "Persuasive", "Narrative", "Descriptive"], "correctAnswer": "Narrative" },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "When writing a narrative, what type of devices are recommended to be used?", "options": ["Only simple sentences", "Transitional devices", "Complex vocabulary only", "Repetitive phrases"], "correctAnswer": "Transitional devices" }
  ],
  "The Lake Isle of Innisfree (Nature)": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What is Unit 3 primarily about?", "options": ["Festivals", "Role Models", "Nature", "Social Evils"], "correctAnswer": "Nature" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "Who is the author of 'The Lake Isle of Innisfree'?", "options": ["Robert Frost", "William Butler Yeats", "Emily Dickinson", "John Keats"], "correctAnswer": "William Butler Yeats" },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "What does the poet want to build in Innisfree?", "options": ["A large house", "A small cabin of clay and wattles", "A luxurious villa", "A treehouse"], "correctAnswer": "A small cabin of clay and wattles" },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "How many bean-rows does the poet want to plant in Innisfree?", "options": ["Five", "Seven", "Nine", "Ten"], "correctAnswer": "Nine" },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "What does the poet wish to have for the honey-bee?", "options": ["A hive", "Flowers", "A garden", "A tree"], "correctAnswer": "A hive" },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "What sound does the poet anticipate hearing in the bee-loud glade?", "options": ["Birdsong", "Buzzing of bees", "Water lapping", "Cricket sings"], "correctAnswer": "Buzzing of bees" },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "What kind of peace does the poet desire in Innisfree?", "options": ["Political peace", "Peace comes dropping slow", "Absolute quiet", "Mental peace"], "correctAnswer": "Peace comes dropping slow" },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "What sounds will the poet hear when he goes to Innisfree at night and day?", "options": ["The sound of crickets singing at midnight", "The sound of the linnet's wings at evening full", "Lake water lapping with low sounds by the shore", "All of the above"], "correctAnswer": "All of the above" },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "Where does the poet hear the sound of the lake water lapping?", "options": ["In his dreams", "In his deep heart's core", "On the road", "By the water's edge"], "correctAnswer": "In his deep heart's core" },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "What is the central theme of 'The Lake Isle of Innisfree'?", "options": ["Urban life", "Nature and tranquility", "Adventure", "Social issues"], "correctAnswer": "Nature and tranquility" },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "In the dialogue, Rosham asks Babar about what fruit?", "options": ["Apples", "Grapes", "Mangoes from Multan", "Peaches"], "correctAnswer": "Mangoes from Multan" },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "Babar mentions that 'Fruits are essential in a healthy diet.' This statement is part of a:", "options": ["Reading comprehension", "Group work discussion", "Vocabulary exercise", "Grammar lesson"], "correctAnswer": "Group work discussion" },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "What does 'wattles' mean in the context of the poem?", "options": ["Construction material", "Small animals", "Trees", "Type of flower"], "correctAnswer": "Construction material" },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "'Glade' refers to a:", "options": ["forest", "grassland", "mountain", "river"], "correctAnswer": "grassland" },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'glimmer'?", "options": ["darkness", "shine", "dullness", "shadow"], "correctAnswer": "shine" },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "A 'linnet' is a type of:", "options": ["fish", "bird", "tree", "flower"], "correctAnswer": "bird" },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "What does 'pavements' refer to?", "options": ["Roads for vehicles", "Paved path at the side of a road for pedestrians", "Natural paths", "Garden paths"], "correctAnswer": "Paved path at the side of a road for pedestrians" },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "What is an 'affix'?", "options": ["A word that stands alone", "A word element that is used to alter the meaning or form of a word", "A synonym", "An antonym"], "correctAnswer": "A word element that is used to alter the meaning or form of a word" },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "A prefix is a letter or group of letters added to the ______ of a word.", "options": ["end", "middle", "beginning", "anywhere"], "correctAnswer": "beginning" },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "A suffix is a letter or group of letters added to the ______ of a word.", "options": ["beginning", "middle", "end", "anywhere"], "correctAnswer": "end" },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "What is the suffix for the word 'hopeful'?", "options": ["hope", "ful", "hopefully", "less"], "correctAnswer": "ful" },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "What is the root word for 'auditory'?", "options": ["audi", "auditor", "audio", "audit"], "correctAnswer": "audi" },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "Which prefix means 'above' or 'beyond'?", "options": ["super-", "anti-", "pre-", "re-"], "correctAnswer": "super-" },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "Which suffix indicates 'quality' or 'state'?", "options": ["-ment", "-ness", "-able", "-tion"], "correctAnswer": "-ness" },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "The suffix '-able' means:", "options": ["capable of", "full of", "without", "pertaining to"], "correctAnswer": "capable of" },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "An article is a word that comes before a noun to show if it's:", "options": ["a pronoun", "specific or general", "an adjective", "a verb"], "correctAnswer": "specific or general" },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "'The' is what type of article?", "options": ["Indefinite", "Definite", "Common", "Proper"], "correctAnswer": "Definite" },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "'A' and 'an' are what type of articles?", "options": ["Definite", "Indefinite", "Demonstrative", "Possessive"], "correctAnswer": "Indefinite" },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "Use 'a' before words that begin with a:", "options": ["vowel sound", "consonant sound", "silent letter", "specific noun"], "correctAnswer": "consonant sound" },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "Use 'an' before words that begin with a:", "options": ["consonant sound", "vowel sound", "silent letter", "specific noun"], "correctAnswer": "vowel sound" },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "Reciprocal pronouns refer to a situation where:", "options": ["someone or something performs an action on another", "someone or something performs an action on others and receives the same action in return", "an action is performed by oneself", "a general action takes place"], "correctAnswer": "someone or something performs an action on others and receives the same action in return" },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "Which of the following is a reciprocal pronoun?", "options": ["myself", "himself", "each other", "themselves"], "correctAnswer": "each other" },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "In 'Laiba and Maham are playing with each other,' what type of pronoun is 'each other'?", "options": ["Reflexive", "Personal", "Reciprocal", "Demonstrative"], "correctAnswer": "Reciprocal" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "Reflexive pronouns are used when the subject, as well as the object, is:", "options": ["different people", "the same person", "a group", "an animal"], "correctAnswer": "the same person" },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "Reflexive pronouns always end in:", "options": ["-tion or -sion", "-er or -or", "-self or -selves", "-ing or -ed"], "correctAnswer": "-self or -selves" },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "Complete the sentence with a reflexive pronoun: 'You are too young to do it ______.'", "options": ["yourself", "yourselves", "myself", "herself"], "correctAnswer": "yourself" },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "What is the structure of a Subject-verb-adverb (SVA) pattern sentence?", "options": ["Subject + verb + noun", "Subject + verb + adjective", "Subject + verb + adverb", "Adverb + subject + verb"], "correctAnswer": "Subject + verb + adverb" },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "In 'He swims well,' what is the adverb?", "options": ["He", "swims", "well", "He swims"], "correctAnswer": "well" },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "In 'The dog jumps high,' what is the verb?", "options": ["The dog", "jumps", "high", "jumps high"], "correctAnswer": "jumps" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "The Present Continuous Tense indicates an action happening in the:", "options": ["past", "future", "present and may continue into the future", "any time"], "correctAnswer": "present and may continue into the future" },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "What is the affirmative structure for Present Continuous Tense?", "options": ["Subject + is/am/are + verb-ing + object.", "Subject + has/have + verb (3rd form) + object.", "Subject + verb (present form) + object.", "Subject + will/shall + verb (present form) + object."], "correctAnswer": "Subject + is/am/are + verb-ing + object." },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "Change the sentence 'They are walking' into its negative form:", "options": ["They are not walking.", "They walking not.", "They walk not.", "They do not walk."], "correctAnswer": "They are not walking." },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "Fill in the blank: '______ you helping your grandmama?'", "options": ["Am", "Are", "Is", "Do"], "correctAnswer": "Are" },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "What is a 'narrative paragraph'?", "options": ["A paragraph that explains a process", "A paragraph that tells about an event", "A paragraph that persuades", "A paragraph that compares and contrasts"], "correctAnswer": "A paragraph that tells about an event" },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "When writing a narrative, what should be done with transitional words and phrases?", "options": ["Avoid them", "Use a variety of them", "Use only one type", "Use them sparingly"], "correctAnswer": "Use a variety of them" },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "Which part of a narrative tells about the key beginning, middle, and an ending?", "options": ["Plot", "Character", "Theme", "Setting"], "correctAnswer": "Plot" },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "What does 'chronological order of arranging details' refer to in narrative writing?", "options": ["Arranging details by importance", "Arranging details by category", "Arranging details in the order they happened in time", "Arranging details based on emotional impact"], "correctAnswer": "Arranging details in the order they happened in time" },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "What is the benefit of using 'vivid verbs, modifiers, etc.' in narrative writing?", "options": ["To make the writing longer", "To make the writing more confusing", "To make the writing lively", "To make the writing monotonous"], "correctAnswer": "To make the writing lively" },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "What is the purpose of punctuation marks like capitalization, exclamation marks, and full stops in writing?", "options": ["To add color", "To indicate pauses and emphasis", "To make the text shorter", "To confuse the reader"], "correctAnswer": "To indicate pauses and emphasis" },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "A narrative text should include:", "options": ["A topic sentence", "Supporting details", "A conclusion", "All of the above"], "correctAnswer": "All of the above" }
  ],
  "Major Shabbir Sharif Shaheed (Role Models)": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What is Unit 4 about, according to the Table of Content?", "options": ["Peaceful Co-existence", "Role Models", "Crisis Management", "Patriotism"], "correctAnswer": "Role Models" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "Where was Major Muhammad Sharif's father born?", "options": ["Lahore, Pakistan", "Kunjah, Gujrat", "Rawalpindi", "Multan"], "correctAnswer": "Kunjah, Gujrat" },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "Who was Major Shabbir Sharif Shaheed's uncle?", "options": ["Major Rana Muhammad Sharif", "Major Raja Aziz Bhatti", "Raheel Sharif", "General Zia ul Haq"], "correctAnswer": "Major Raja Aziz Bhatti" },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "Which institution did Major Shabbir Sharif attend for his matriculation?", "options": ["Army Public School", "Saint Anthony's High School, Lahore", "Cadet College", "Military Academy"], "correctAnswer": "Saint Anthony's High School, Lahore" },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "Major Shabbir Sharif received the 'Sword of Honour' for what achievement?", "options": ["For winning a war", "For his academic excellence", "For being the best outgoing cadet from Pakistan Military Academy", "For his leadership skills"], "correctAnswer": "For being the best outgoing cadet from Pakistan Military Academy" },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "When did Major Shabbir Sharif Shaheed's unit attack the Indian forces in the Sulemanki Sector?", "options": ["December 1st, 1971", "December 3rd, 1971", "December 5th, 1971", "December 6th, 1971"], "correctAnswer": "December 3rd, 1971" },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "Major Shabbir Sharif was a commander of a company from which regiment?", "options": ["Sindh Regiment", "Punjab Regiment", "Frontier Force Regiment", "Baluch Regiment"], "correctAnswer": "Frontier Force Regiment" },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "What obstacle did Major Shabbir Sharif face during the battle in the Sulemanki Sector?", "options": ["A river", "A dense forest", "A wide, deep, and strongly defended ditch", "A mountain range"], "correctAnswer": "A wide, deep, and strongly defended ditch" },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "How many Indian soldiers were captured by Major Shabbir Sharif's company?", "options": ["10", "15", "20", "25"], "correctAnswer": "25" },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "What was Major Shabbir Sharif's main task on December 5th, 1971?", "options": ["To destroy Indian tanks", "To capture a specific object", "To defend their positions", "To retreat"], "correctAnswer": "To capture a specific object" },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "How many enemy tanks did Major Shabbir Sharif's company destroy?", "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four", "Five"], "correctAnswer": "Four" },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "What was the highest military award received by Major Shabbir Sharif Shaheed?", "options": ["Sitara-e-Jurat", "Hilal-e-Jurat", "Nishan-e-Haider", "Tamgha-e-Basalat"], "correctAnswer": "Nishan-e-Haider" },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "How many Indian battalions attacked on December 6th, after Shabbir Sharif had captured his objective?", "options": ["One", "Two", "Three", "Four"], "correctAnswer": "Two" },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "How old was Major Shabbir Sharif Shaheed when he embraced martyrdom?", "options": ["25 years old", "28 years old", "30 years old", "32 years old"], "correctAnswer": "28 years old" },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "In the dialogue, Azhar's childhood friend Mr. Rahman is:", "options": ["A doctor", "A lieutenant in the Pakistan Army", "A teacher", "A businessman"], "correctAnswer": "A lieutenant in the Pakistan Army" },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "What does 'assets' mean?", "options": ["liabilities", "a person or thing that is valuable or useful", "problems", "challenges"], "correctAnswer": "a person or thing that is valuable or useful" },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "The meaning of 'capture' is:", "options": ["to release", "to take control of", "to surrender", "to observe"], "correctAnswer": "to take control of" },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "What does 'fearlessly' mean?", "options": ["with fear", "without being afraid", "cautiously", "nervously"], "correctAnswer": "without being afraid" },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "'Martyrdom' means:", "options": ["victory", "defeat", "death of a martyr", "bravery"], "correctAnswer": "death of a martyr" },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "What is a 'simile'?", "options": ["A comparison using 'like' or 'as'", "A direct comparison", "An exaggeration", "A word that imitates a sound"], "correctAnswer": "A comparison using 'like' or 'as'" },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "Complete the simile: 'as clear as a ______'", "options": ["bell", "crystal", "day", "whistle"], "correctAnswer": "crystal" },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "What does the simile 'as busy as a bee' mean?", "options": ["very slow", "very active", "very quiet", "very sleepy"], "correctAnswer": "very active" },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "What does 'as light as a feather' mean?", "options": ["very heavy", "very dark", "very light", "very fast"], "correctAnswer": "very light" },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "Which phrasal verb means 'to help someone blow up balloons'?", "options": ["blow up", "get angry", "carry on", "agree with"], "correctAnswer": "blow up" },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "What is the meaning of the phrasal verb 'get angry'?", "options": ["to become happy", "to become furious", "to become sad", "to become calm"], "correctAnswer": "to become furious" },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "What does the idiom 'lend a hand' mean?", "options": ["to give money", "to provide help", "to borrow something", "to wave goodbye"], "correctAnswer": "to provide help" },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "'It's raining cats and dogs' is an idiom for:", "options": ["light rain", "heavy rain", "no rain", "a sunny day"], "correctAnswer": "heavy rain" },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "What does the idiom 'kill two birds with one stone' mean?", "options": ["to waste time", "to get nothing done", "to achieve two things with a single action", "to cause trouble"], "correctAnswer": "to achieve two things with a single action" },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "What does 'under the weather' mean idiomatically?", "options": ["feeling great", "feeling unwell", "feeling hot", "feeling cold"], "correctAnswer": "feeling unwell" },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "An adjective is a word used to describe a:", "options": ["verb, action, or state", "person, place, or thing", "linking word", "punctuation mark"], "correctAnswer": "person, place, or thing" },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "Adjectives modify:", "options": ["verbs or adverbs", "nouns or pronouns", "prepositions or conjunctions", "sentences or paragraphs"], "correctAnswer": "nouns or pronouns" },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "'One, two, few, many, a lot' are examples of adjectives of:", "options": ["Quality", "Size", "Quantity", "Shape"], "correctAnswer": "Quantity" },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "'Nice, beautiful, excellent, kind' are examples of adjectives of:", "options": ["Quantity", "Quality", "Color", "Origin"], "correctAnswer": "Quality" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "What is the correct order of adjectives?", "options": ["Quality, size, shape, color, origin", "Size, quality, shape, color, origin", "Color, size, quality, shape, origin", "Shape, color, size, quality, origin"], "correctAnswer": "Quality, size, shape, color, origin" },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "What is a 'Pronoun antecedent agreement'?", "options": ["When a pronoun and verb agree in number.", "When a pronoun agrees in number, gender, and person with its antecedent.", "When a pronoun agrees with an adjective.", "When a pronoun is placed before the noun."], "correctAnswer": "When a pronoun agrees in number, gender, and person with its antecedent." },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "In 'Chelsey finished her presentation, 'Chelsey' is the antecedent and 'her' is the pronoun,' the pronoun refers to:", "options": ["the verb", "the adjective", "the noun that precedes it", "the subject"], "correctAnswer": "the noun that precedes it" },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "How many types of sentences are discussed in Unit 4?", "options": ["One", "Two", "Three", "Four"], "correctAnswer": "Four" },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "A sentence that contains only one independent clause is a:", "options": ["Compound sentence", "Complex sentence", "Simple sentence", "Compound-complex sentence"], "correctAnswer": "Simple sentence" },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "A compound sentence contains how many independent clauses?", "options": ["One", "Two or more", "Zero", "Depends on context"], "correctAnswer": "Two or more" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "What typically connects clauses in a compound sentence?", "options": ["Adverbs", "Commas or connectors", "Prepositions", "Adjectives"], "correctAnswer": "Commas or connectors" },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "The Past Continuous Tense describes actions or events in a time before now, which:", "options": ["began in the past and ended in the past.", "began in the past and were still going on when another event occurred.", "are happening now.", "will happen in the future."], "correctAnswer": "began in the past and were still going on when another event occurred." },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "What is the affirmative structure for Past Continuous Tense?", "options": ["Subject + was/were + verb-ing + object.", "Subject + has/have + verb (3rd form) + object.", "Subject + did + verb (present form) + object.", "Subject + verb (past form) + object."], "correctAnswer": "Subject + was/were + verb-ing + object." },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "What is a 'Gerund'?", "options": ["A verb that acts as an adjective.", "A verb form ending in -ing that acts as a noun.", "A verb form used in continuous tenses.", "A verb that expresses action."], "correctAnswer": "A verb form ending in -ing that acts as a noun." },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "In 'Teaching is my passion,' 'teaching' is used as a:", "options": ["verb", "adjective", "gerund", "participle"], "correctAnswer": "gerund" },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "In 'He is teaching English,' 'teaching' is used as a:", "options": ["gerund", "participle", "noun", "adverb"], "correctAnswer": "participle" },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "What is a 'Book Blurb'?", "options": ["The title of a book.", "The text on the back side of the book, which is a summary.", "The author's biography.", "The table of contents."], "correctAnswer": "The text on the back side of the book, which is a summary." },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "What is the aim of a book blurb?", "options": ["To give all details of the story.", "To get a reader interested in a book.", "To reveal the ending.", "To analyze the plot."], "correctAnswer": "To get a reader interested in a book." },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "What should you 'Look at' to introduce the topic and write a short paragraph on it?", "options": ["A book blurb", "A poster and illustrations", "A story", "A dialogue"], "correctAnswer": "A poster and illustrations" },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "What type of vocabulary should be used when writing a paragraph based on a poster?", "options": ["Complex vocabulary", "Precise language and domain specific vocabulary", "General vocabulary", "Slang"], "correctAnswer": "Precise language and domain specific vocabulary" },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "What is the topic sentence example provided for an essay on sports and games?", "options": ["Sports are fun.", "Sports and games play a major role in keeping a person fit and healthy.", "Sports should be played every day.", "Games are for children."], "correctAnswer": "Sports and games play a major role in keeping a person fit and healthy." }
  ],
  "Harmony in Society (Peaceful Co-existence / Peace Education)": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What is the main theme of Unit 5, as listed in the Table of Content?", "options": ["Crisis Management and Risk Reduction", "Overpopulation - A Dilemma", "Peaceful Co-existence / Peace Education", "Avoiding Social Evils"], "correctAnswer": "Peaceful Co-existence / Peace Education" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "What is one of the student learning outcomes for Unit 5 related to listening and understanding?", "options": ["To listen passively to conversations.", "To respond only to direct questions.", "To summarize texts without detailed comprehension.", "To listen to, view, and respond to texts for different purposes in a variety of contexts for enjoyment and understanding."], "correctAnswer": "To listen to, view, and respond to texts for different purposes in a variety of contexts for enjoyment and understanding." },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "According to the learning outcomes, what skill related to dictionary/thesaurus use is expected from students in Unit 5?", "options": ["To locate synonyms only.", "To locate antonyms only.", "To use dictionary/thesaurus to: locate guide words, locate entry words, choose appropriate word definition, identify appropriate pronunciation key, identify syllable division, identify the part of speech of a word through abbreviation used.", "To use a dictionary for spelling checks only."], "correctAnswer": "To use dictionary/thesaurus to: locate guide words, locate entry words, choose appropriate word definition, identify appropriate pronunciation key, identify syllable division, identify the part of speech of a word through abbreviation used." },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "Which grammar concept is focused on for distinguishing and recognizing forms of adjectives in Unit 5?", "options": ["Adjective clauses", "Adjective phrases", "Degrees of Adjectives (Positive, Comparative, Superlative)", "Possessive adjectives"], "correctAnswer": "Degrees of Adjectives (Positive, Comparative, Superlative)" },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "What is the primary function of 'Transitional Devices' as taught in Unit 5's grammar section?", "options": ["To mark the end of a sentence", "To introduce new characters in a story", "To describe nouns in detail", "To link sentences and paragraphs / for adding something to the sentences"], "correctAnswer": "To link sentences and paragraphs / for adding something to the sentences" },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "Which type of pronouns is introduced in Unit 5 for grammar study?", "options": ["Interrogative pronouns", "Demonstrative pronouns", "Relative pronouns", "Indefinite pronouns"], "correctAnswer": "Relative pronouns" },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "What verb tense is explicitly covered in the grammar section of Unit 5?", "options": ["Simple Past Tense", "Future Perfect Tense", "Present Perfect Tense", "Past Continuous Tense"], "correctAnswer": "Present Perfect Tense" },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "What is the purpose of the 'Pre-reading' section in Unit 5, based on the question asked to students?", "options": ["To review vocabulary from the previous unit.", "To introduce the main characters of the story.", "To prompt discussion about personal experiences related to behavior.", "To outline the plot of the upcoming reading."], "correctAnswer": "To prompt discussion about personal experiences related to behavior." },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "Who are the main characters in the reading comprehension passage of Unit 5?", "options": ["Shiza and Tania", "Danish and his grandfather", "Haziq and Ahmad", "Usman and Maryam"], "correctAnswer": "Haziq and Ahmad" },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "What activity were Haziq and Ahmad engaged in when they saw the new neighbors moving in?", "options": ["Playing football", "Reading books", "Playing in their ground, throwing a ball", "Watching TV"], "correctAnswer": "Playing in their ground, throwing a ball" },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "What did Haziq and Ahmad's mother prepare for them to give to the new neighbors?", "options": ["A fruit basket", "A bowl of dessert", "A homemade cake", "Some fresh juice"], "correctAnswer": "A bowl of dessert" },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "How did the new neighbors react to Haziq and Ahmad's visit?", "options": ["They ignored them.", "They were rude to them.", "They greeted them with a broad smile and great respect.", "They asked them to leave."], "correctAnswer": "They greeted them with a broad smile and great respect." },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "What did the neighbors' daughter offer to Haziq and Ahmad?", "options": ["Cookies", "Water", "Juice", "Candy"], "correctAnswer": "Cookies" },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "What did Haziq and Ahmad forget to do before leaving their house that resulted in damage?", "options": ["Lock the door", "Turn off the lights", "Close the window", "Feed their pet"], "correctAnswer": "Close the window" },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "What was the reaction of the boy from the new neighbors to Haziq and Ahmad's open window?", "options": ["He helped them close it.", "He informed his parents.", "He threw a ball and broke the window.", "He walked away without noticing."], "correctAnswer": "He threw a ball and broke the window." },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "How did Haziq and Ahmad initially feel after the incident with the broken window?", "options": ["Happy", "Angry", "Devastated", "Excited"], "correctAnswer": "Devastated" },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "What was Jasim's physical condition as described in the story?", "options": ["He was deaf.", "He had difficulty speaking.", "He had polio and his leg was paralyzed.", "He was blind."], "correctAnswer": "He had polio and his leg was paralyzed." },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "How did Haziq and Ahmad's perception of Jasim change after learning about his situation?", "options": ["They started to fear him.", "They wanted to avoid him.", "They realized the importance of empathy and making him a productive part of thinking.", "They felt disgusted."], "correctAnswer": "They realized the importance of empathy and making him a productive part of thinking." },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "What moral lesson is derived from the interaction with Jasim in the story?", "options": ["One should always compete to be the best.", "It is important to avoid difficult situations.", "It is our moral duty to treat people like Jasim with empathy.", "Focus on your own problems first."], "correctAnswer": "It is our moral duty to treat people like Jasim with empathy." },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "In the vocabulary section of Unit 5, what is the meaning of the word 'devastated'?", "options": ["Excited", "Thrilled", "Shocked", "Happy"], "correctAnswer": "Shocked" },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "What does 'reluctant' mean as per the vocabulary list in Unit 5?", "options": ["Enthusiastic", "Eager", "Unwilling", "Willing"], "correctAnswer": "Unwilling" },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'dysfunctional' in the context of Unit 5's vocabulary?", "options": ["Normal", "Working properly", "Abnormal", "Efficient"], "correctAnswer": "Abnormal" },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "How many degrees of adjectives are taught in Unit 5?", "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four", "Five"], "correctAnswer": "Three" },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "What is the definition of the 'Positive' degree of an adjective?", "options": ["It compares two subjects.", "It expresses the highest quality.", "It is the primary degree which denotes the quality of a subject without any comparison.", "It indicates a decrease in quality."], "correctAnswer": "It is the primary degree which denotes the quality of a subject without any comparison." },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "How are irregular adjectives different from regular adjectives in forming their comparative and superlative degrees?", "options": ["They follow the same rule of adding -er/-est.", "They only add 'more' or 'most'.", "They do not change their form by adding -er/-est or more/most.", "They do not have comparative or superlative forms."], "correctAnswer": "They do not change their form by adding -er/-est or more/most." },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "What is the comparative form of the adjective 'sharp'?", "options": ["Sharpest", "Sharply", "Sharper", "More sharp"], "correctAnswer": "Sharper" },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "What is the superlative form of the adjective 'low'?", "options": ["Lower", "Lowerest", "Lowest", "More low"], "correctAnswer": "Lowest" },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "What is the positive degree of the adjective for which 'further' is the comparative?", "options": ["Near", "Close", "Far", "Distant"], "correctAnswer": "Far" },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "What is the superlative degree of the adjective 'strong'?", "options": ["Stronger", "Most strong", "Strongest", "More strong"], "correctAnswer": "Strongest" },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "Which of the following is NOT listed as a transitional device in Unit 5?", "options": ["Besides", "Along with", "In addition to", "Therefore"], "correctAnswer": "Therefore" },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "What type of clauses do 'Relative Pronouns' head?", "options": ["Adverb clauses", "Noun clauses", "Adjective clauses", "Independent clauses"], "correctAnswer": "Adjective clauses" },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "Which relative pronoun is used for things when they are the subject or object of the clause?", "options": ["Who", "Whom", "Which", "Whose"], "correctAnswer": "Which" },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "Complete the sentence with the correct relative pronoun: 'The girl _______ I was talking to is a good friend.'", "options": ["Which", "That", "Whom", "Whose"], "correctAnswer": "Whom" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "What defines a 'Clause' in grammar?", "options": ["A group of words that functions as a single part of speech.", "A group of words that have a subject and a verb.", "A single word.", "A punctuation mark."], "correctAnswer": "A group of words that have a subject and a verb." },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "What is the key characteristic of an 'Independent Clause'?", "options": ["It always begins with a subordinating conjunction.", "It depends on another clause for its meaning.", "It can make sense on its own as a sentence.", "It describes a noun."], "correctAnswer": "It can make sense on its own as a sentence." },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "What is the definition of a 'Dependent Clause'?", "options": ["It is also known as a main clause.", "It cannot make sense on its own as a sentence.", "It always expresses a complete thought.", "It contains only a subject."], "correctAnswer": "It cannot make sense on its own as a sentence." },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "Which type of phrase is 'Very beautiful' according to the examples in Unit 5?", "options": ["Noun phrase", "Adverb phrase", "Adjective phrase", "Prepositional phrase"], "correctAnswer": "Adjective phrase" },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "What is the structure for the affirmative form of the Present Perfect Tense?", "options": ["Subject + has/have + Verb (3rd form) + object", "Subject + verb (past form) + object", "Subject + has/have + Verb (3rd form) + object", "Subject + will + verb (base form) + object"], "correctAnswer": "Subject + has/have + Verb (3rd form) + object" },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "For which subjects do we use 'has' in the Present Perfect Tense?", "options": ["I, we, you, they, and plural subjects", "He, she, it, and singular subject", "Only I and you", "All subjects"], "correctAnswer": "He, she, it, and singular subject" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "What is the negative structure of the Present Perfect Tense?", "options": ["Subject + did not + verb (base form) + object", "Subject + has/have + verb (3rd form) + not + object", "Subject + has/have + not + verb (3rd form) + object", "Subject + will not + verb (base form) + object"], "correctAnswer": "Subject + has/have + not + verb (3rd form) + object" },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'Literal Meanings' as defined in Unit 5?", "options": ["The figurative or symbolic meaning.", "The hidden or implied meaning.", "The actual meaning of a word or phrase, based on its dictionary meaning.", "The meaning that changes based on context."], "correctAnswer": "The actual meaning of a word or phrase, based on its dictionary meaning." },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "What defines 'Non-literal Meanings' in the provided source?", "options": ["Meanings that are always scientific.", "Meanings of words and phrases (also called figurative language) because they are often odd or unrealistic.", "Meanings that are directly from a dictionary.", "Meanings that are straightforward and clear."], "correctAnswer": "Meanings of words and phrases (also called figurative language) because they are often odd or unrealistic." },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "In the sentence 'My head is in the clouds,' what is the non-literal meaning of the phrase 'in the clouds'?", "options": ["Dreaming about rain", "Physically located above the ground", "Day dreaming", "Feeling dizzy"], "correctAnswer": "Day dreaming" },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "According to the example provided, what is the literal meaning of 'left a bad taste in my mouth'?", "options": ["Ate something unpleasant", "Had a good taste experience", "Experienced a bad situation", "Tasted something sweet"], "correctAnswer": "Ate something unpleasant" },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "What is the rule for using a comma before a conjunction according to Unit 5's punctuation rules?", "options": ["Use a comma after an introductory word.", "Use a comma to separate items in a series.", "Use a pair of commas to set off interruptions.", "Use a comma before a conjunction that joins main clauses."], "correctAnswer": "Use a comma before a conjunction that joins main clauses." },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "What does the 'Learn It!' box in the 'Multi-syllable words' section compare an 'analogy' to?", "options": ["A type of dictionary entry", "A comparison between two things, usually to explain or clarify something", "A specific grammar rule", "A way to write narratives"], "correctAnswer": "A comparison between two things, usually to explain or clarify something" },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "What is the multi-syllable word for 'A person whose work is to establish something'?", "options": ["Uncomfortable", "Environment", "Mountains", "Establishment"], "correctAnswer": "Establishment" },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "What is the multi-syllable word that means 'not feeling comfortable'?", "options": ["Environment", "Establishment", "Uncomfortable", "Beautiful"], "correctAnswer": "Uncomfortable" },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'gloomy' in the vocabulary section of Unit 5?", "options": ["Excited", "Thrilled", "Happy", "Sad"], "correctAnswer": "Sad" },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'slanted' in the review vocabulary?", "options": ["Upright", "Oblique", "Straight", "Level"], "correctAnswer": "Oblique" }
  ],
  "First Aid Saves Life (Crisis Management and Risk Reduction)": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What is the main theme of Unit 6?", "options": ["Harmony in Society", "Overpopulation - a Dilemma", "Crisis Management and Risk Reduction", "Avoiding Social Evils"], "correctAnswer": "Crisis Management and Risk Reduction" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "What was Tina doing on her way back that led to the incident?", "options": ["Walking to school", "Playing with friends", "Observed a crowd of people on the road and a woman lying collapsed.", "Listening to music"], "correctAnswer": "Observed a crowd of people on the road and a woman lying collapsed." },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "Who was the woman that collapsed on the road?", "options": ["Tina's neighbor", "Tina's mother", "Tina's teacher", "A stranger"], "correctAnswer": "Tina's mother" },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "What did Tina do immediately after seeing her mother collapsed?", "options": ["Panicked and ran away.", "Called her father.", "Moved the crowd away and tried talking to the lady.", "Waited for an ambulance."], "correctAnswer": "Moved the crowd away and tried talking to the lady." },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "What did Tina do to check her mother's condition while waiting for an ambulance?", "options": ["Gave her water.", "Checked her breathing and pulse.", "Called a doctor.", "Tried to wake her up."], "correctAnswer": "Checked her breathing and pulse." },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "What technique did Tina use to give her mother rescue breaths?", "options": ["Administered an injection.", "Put her hands on her chest and provided 30 uninterrupted chest compressions.", "Massaged her arms.", "Elevated her legs."], "correctAnswer": "Put her hands on her chest and provided 30 uninterrupted chest compressions." },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "What is Tina's profession or area of study?", "options": ["She is a lawyer.", "She is a nurse.", "She is a medical student.", "She is an engineer."], "correctAnswer": "She is a medical student." },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "What skill did Tina use to save her mother's life?", "options": ["Advanced medical surgery", "Professional driving", "Cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR)", "Calling emergency services"], "correctAnswer": "Cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR)" },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "What is the definition of 'Cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR)' according to the text?", "options": ["A technique to stop bleeding.", "A lifesaving method that is useful in many emergencies.", "A method to diagnose diseases.", "A form of physical exercise."], "correctAnswer": "A lifesaving method that is useful in many emergencies." },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "What is the common cause for the need of CPR, as mentioned in the text?", "options": ["Broken bones", "Heart attack or near drowning, in which someone's breathing or heartbeat has stopped.", "Allergic reactions", "High fever"], "correctAnswer": "Heart attack or near drowning, in which someone's breathing or heartbeat has stopped." },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "What was the family's reaction to Tina's action?", "options": ["They were angry with her.", "They were indifferent.", "They were really grateful.", "They blamed her."], "correctAnswer": "They were really grateful." },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "What does the idiom 'lend a hand' mean in Unit 6's vocabulary section?", "options": ["To borrow something", "To take something", "To provide help", "To shake hands"], "correctAnswer": "To provide help" },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "What is the meaning of the idiom 'it's raining cats and dogs'?", "options": ["Animals are falling from the sky.", "It's snowing heavily.", "It's raining hard.", "There are many pets outside."], "correctAnswer": "It's raining hard." },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "What does the idiom 'kill two birds with one stone' signify?", "options": ["To harm animals.", "To solve one problem quickly.", "To get two things done with a single action.", "To throw stones."], "correctAnswer": "To get two things done with a single action." },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'bread and butter' as an idiom?", "options": ["A type of meal.", "A basic food item.", "Someone's livelihood.", "A cooking ingredient."], "correctAnswer": "Someone's livelihood." },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "What does the idiom 'hit the sack' mean?", "options": ["To hit a bag.", "To go shopping.", "To go to sleep.", "To start working."], "correctAnswer": "To go to sleep." },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'no pain, no gain' in the idioms section?", "options": ["You must avoid pain.", "You will not feel pain.", "You must work for what you want.", "Pain is always bad."], "correctAnswer": "You must work for what you want." },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "What is the function of 'Conjunctions' in grammar, as described in Unit 6?", "options": ["To describe nouns.", "Words that connect two phrases or clauses.", "To express emotion.", "To indicate time."], "correctAnswer": "Words that connect two phrases or clauses." },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "What is a key characteristic of 'Transitional devices' as explained in Unit 6's grammar section?", "options": ["They only connect individual words.", "They are always verbs.", "Words or phrases that indicate the relationship between two sentences or paragraphs.", "They remove a conjunction from a sentence."], "correctAnswer": "Words or phrases that indicate the relationship between two sentences or paragraphs." },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "Which of the following is NOT listed as a conjunction example used for reason?", "options": ["And", "But", "Because", "Therefore"], "correctAnswer": "Therefore" },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "Complete the sentence using a suitable conjunction: 'I like mangoes _______ apples.'", "options": ["But", "And", "Because", "If"], "correctAnswer": "And" },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "Which transitional word means 'as a result and etc.'?", "options": ["Before", "Then", "Therefore", "While"], "correctAnswer": "Therefore" },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "What is the suffix used to form an adjective from the noun 'luck'?", "options": ["-al", "-ial", "-ish", "-y"], "correctAnswer": "-y" },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "How is the adjective 'financial' formed from a noun?", "options": ["By adding -y", "By adding -al", "By adding -ial", "By adding -ic"], "correctAnswer": "-ial" },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "From what noun is the adjective 'artistic' formed, according to the table in Unit 6?", "options": ["Artisty", "Artful", "Artist", "Artism"], "correctAnswer": "Artist" },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "What type of clause is a 'Comparative Clause'?", "options": ["An independent clause", "A main clause", "A type of subordinate clause that follows the comparative form of an adjective or adverb and begins with as, than, or like.", "A clause that expresses a question."], "correctAnswer": "A type of subordinate clause that follows the comparative form of an adjective or adverb and begins with as, than, or like." },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "What pronouns are listed as initiating 'Relative Clauses'?", "options": ["I, you, he, she", "This, that, these, those", "Who, which, whom, that", "Myself, yourself, himself"], "correctAnswer": "Who, which, whom, that" },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "What is the definition of a 'Relative Clause'?", "options": ["A clause that describes an action.", "A clause that shows comparison.", "A subordinate clause which specifies or gives information about a person or thing.", "A clause that expresses a complete thought."], "correctAnswer": "A subordinate clause which specifies or gives information about a person or thing." },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "What is the structure for the affirmative form of the Past Perfect Tense?", "options": ["Subject + has/have + Verb (3rd form) + object", "Subject + verb (past form) + object", "Subject + had + past participle form of verb.", "Subject + will + verb (base form) + object"], "correctAnswer": "Subject + had + past participle form of verb." },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "When is the Past Perfect Tense used?", "options": ["For an action that started in the past and is still continuing.", "To talk about things that haven't happened yet.", "To describe an action that happens regularly.", "For past action, already finished when another past action happened. It also use for unreal and imaginary things, wishes in the past."], "correctAnswer": "For past action, already finished when another past action happened. It also use for unreal and imaginary things, wishes in the past." },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "How many sentences are given as examples for 'The players had lost heart before the match even finished' in the Past Perfect Tense section?", "options": ["One", "Two", "Three", "Four"], "correctAnswer": "One" },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "When do we use 'for' to talk about the length of time?", "options": ["To talk about a point in the past.", "To talk about the length of time, a period of time.", "To indicate a starting point.", "For a specific point in the future."], "correctAnswer": "To talk about the length of time, a period of time." },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "Which phrase is used with 'since' to indicate a starting point in the past?", "options": ["For two hours", "For three weeks", "For five months", "1st July"], "correctAnswer": "1st July" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "Complete the sentence using 'for' or 'since': 'They've lived in America ______ 2004.'", "options": ["For", "Since", "After", "Before"], "correctAnswer": "Since" },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "What is the purpose of 'Parentheses ()' in punctuation?", "options": ["To introduce a question.", "To mark the end of a sentence.", "To enclose additional information, non-essential information to clarify, explain or add a side note in a sentence.", "To separate items in a list."], "correctAnswer": "To enclose additional information, non-essential information to clarify, explain or add a side note in a sentence." },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "In an informal letter, what information is placed on the top left corner?", "options": ["Date", "Salutation", "Body", "Address"], "correctAnswer": "Address" },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "What is the main message of an informal letter, as per Unit 6?", "options": ["The sender's location", "The date it was written", "The letter is written to the person.", "The complimentary words."], "correctAnswer": "The letter is written to the person." },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "What should be capitalized in the closing of an informal letter?", "options": ["The first letter of the first word only.", "All letters.", "The first letter of the closing line.", "No letters should be capitalized."], "correctAnswer": "The first letter of the first word only." },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "What is the example address given for an informal letter?", "options": ["XYZ, City XYZ", "Lahore, Pakistan", "123, A Block, XYZ, City XYZ", "Punjab, Pakistan"], "correctAnswer": "123, A Block, XYZ, City XYZ" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "What is the specific request mentioned in the example informal letter?", "options": ["To invite to a party.", "To ask about school.", "To share some information with you on covid-19 that I have received from my uncle, Dr. Zian.", "To ask for money."], "correctAnswer": "To share some information with you on covid-19 that I have received from my uncle, Dr. Zian." },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "What is the main health concern mentioned in the example informal letter?", "options": ["Fever", "Cold", "Cough, sore throat, fever, cold, and fatigue due to covid-19 infection.", "Headache"], "correctAnswer": "Cough, sore throat, fever, cold, and fatigue due to covid-19 infection." },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "What is the advice given in the example informal letter to prevent the condition?", "options": ["Take medicines only.", "Stay indoors always.", "Use different simple home remedies as a precaution to avoid infection.", "Avoid eating healthy food."], "correctAnswer": "Use different simple home remedies as a precaution to avoid infection." },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "In the informal letter, what does the closing 'With Love,' indicate?", "options": ["A formal closing.", "An affectionate closing.", "A business closing.", "A request for action."], "correctAnswer": "An affectionate closing." },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "What name is used for the signature in the example informal letter?", "options": ["Saad", "Auntie", "Uncle", "Kaleem"], "correctAnswer": "Kaleem" },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "What type of texts are students expected to comprehend in Unit 6, regarding their purpose?", "options": ["Only humorous texts", "Only factual texts", "Texts for different purposes in a variety of contexts for enjoyment and understanding.", "Texts for critical analysis only"], "correctAnswer": "Texts for different purposes in a variety of contexts for enjoyment and understanding." },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "What type of phrases are students expected to recognize in Unit 6?", "options": ["Noun phrases", "Verb phrases", "Verb and helping verbs", "Independent phrases"], "correctAnswer": "Verb and helping verbs" }
  ],
  "Corruption (Avoiding Social Evils)": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What is the main theme of Unit 7?", "options": ["Harmony in Society", "First Aid Saves Life", "Importance of Science & Technology", "Avoiding Social Evils"], "correctAnswer": "Avoiding Social Evils" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "What is one of the student learning outcomes for Unit 7 related to developing conversation?", "options": ["To engage in debates only.", "To develop conversation for enjoyment.", "To develop conversation for clarity and effect to engage a listener.", "To only discuss social issues."], "correctAnswer": "To develop conversation for clarity and effect to engage a listener." },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "What skill related to dictionary/thesaurus use is expected from students in Unit 7?", "options": ["To locate synonyms only.", "To locate antonyms only.", "To use dictionary/thesaurus to: locate guide words, locate entry words, choose appropriate word definition, identify appropriate pronunciation key, identify syllable division, identify the part of speech of a word through abbreviation used.", "To use a dictionary for spelling checks only."], "correctAnswer": "To use dictionary/thesaurus to: locate guide words, locate entry words, choose appropriate word definition, identify appropriate pronunciation key, identify syllable division, identify the part of speech of a word through abbreviation used." },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "Which grammar concept is focused on for distinguishing and recognizing forms of verbs in Unit 7?", "options": ["Simple Present Tense", "Future Simple Tense", "Modal verbs (can/cannot, may/may not, should, will, shall, could, might etc.)", "Past Continuous Tense"], "correctAnswer": "Modal verbs (can/cannot, may/may not, should, will, shall, could, might etc.)" },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "What skill related to paragraph writing is taught in Unit 7?", "options": ["Writing short poems.", "Summarizing existing texts.", "Writing narratives to develop real or imagined experiences or events using effective techniques, descriptive details, and clear event sequences.", "Writing only about personal experiences."], "correctAnswer": "Writing narratives to develop real or imagined experiences or events using effective techniques, descriptive details, and clear event sequences." },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "Who is the main character in the reading comprehension passage of Unit 7?", "options": ["Mr. Muhammad", "Allah Almighty", "Mr. Shan", "The farmer"], "correctAnswer": "Mr. Shan" },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "What was Mr. Shan's profession?", "options": ["Teacher", "Engineer", "Doctor", "Farmer"], "correctAnswer": "Doctor" },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "What did Mr. Shan do that showed his corruption?", "options": ["He overcharged his patients.", "He misused his power and money.", "He had been issued his signature and today that fake medical certificate had been issued by his signature.", "He cheated on tests."], "correctAnswer": "He had been issued his signature and today that fake medical certificate had been issued by his signature." },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "How did the community react to Mr. Shan's actions?", "options": ["They praised him.", "They were indifferent.", "They were ashamed and repentant when they came to know that he had nothing to say.", "They ignored him."], "correctAnswer": "They were ashamed and repentant when they came to know that he had nothing to say." },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "What did Mr. Shan lose as a result of his corrupt practices?", "options": ["His job.", "His house.", "His honor and had no future plan for his family and the better future of his son.", "His friends."], "correctAnswer": "His honor and had no future plan for his family and the better future of his son." },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "What is the definition of 'Corruption' as presented in the text?", "options": ["A common social practice.", "Misuse of power and money.", "A form of entertainment.", "A type of economic growth."], "correctAnswer": "Misuse of power and money." },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "What does the text state about the consequence of corruption on society?", "options": ["It strengthens society.", "It promotes goodwill.", "It leads to downfall and can destroy society.", "It encourages loyalty."], "correctAnswer": "It leads to downfall and can destroy society." },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'offensive' in the vocabulary section of Unit 7?", "options": ["Pleasant", "Friendly", "Resentful", "Engaging"], "correctAnswer": "Resentful" },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "What does 'bribery' mean?", "options": ["Honesty", "Transparency", "Corruption", "Integrity"], "correctAnswer": "Corruption" },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'devastating'?", "options": ["Happy", "Excited", "Shocking", "Calm"], "correctAnswer": "Shocking" },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "What does 'repentant' mean?", "options": ["Proud", "Uncaring", "Ashamed", "Defiant"], "correctAnswer": "Ashamed" },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "What is an 'Entry Word' in a dictionary?", "options": ["A word's definition.", "Its pronunciation.", "A dictionary entry is a set of information that describes a word or phrase.", "Its origin."], "correctAnswer": "A dictionary entry is a set of information that describes a word or phrase." },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "What does 'Definition' refer to in a dictionary context?", "options": ["How to pronounce a word.", "The word's origin.", "This explains the meaning of the entry word. If there is more than one meaning, the definition is divided by numbers.", "A guide to finding a word."], "correctAnswer": "This explains the meaning of the entry word. If there is more than one meaning, the definition is divided by numbers." },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "What is a 'Guide Word'?", "options": ["A word's part of speech.", "A word or a set of words printed in the top corner of a dictionary page to indicate the first or last item of that page.", "The phonetic spelling.", "The word's history."], "correctAnswer": "A word or a set of words printed in the top corner of a dictionary page to indicate the first or last item of that page." },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "How does the dictionary help with 'Pronunciation'?", "options": ["By providing the word's definition.", "By listing synonyms.", "Words are separated into syllables and teach you how to pronounce the entry word. It tells you which syllable is stressed.", "By showing its origin."], "correctAnswer": "Words are separated into syllables and teach you how to pronounce the entry word. It tells you which syllable is stressed." },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "What information does 'Part of Speech' provide in a dictionary?", "options": ["The plural form of the word.", "Its synonyms.", "This tells you what part of speech the defined word is. It tells you if the entry word is a noun, adjective, verb, pronoun, preposition or conjunction.", "Its etymology."], "correctAnswer": "This tells you what part of speech the defined word is. It tells you if the entry word is a noun, adjective, verb, pronoun, preposition or conjunction." },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "What does 'Origin' refer to in a dictionary entry?", "options": ["The word's meaning.", "How to use the word in a sentence.", "It shows the origin of the entry word.", "Its pronunciation."], "correctAnswer": "It shows the origin of the entry word." },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "What are 'Modal Verbs' used to express?", "options": ["Actions in the past only.", "Regular habits.", "Certain hypothetical conditions, such as advice, capability, or requests.", "Actions that are currently happening."], "correctAnswer": "Certain hypothetical conditions, such as advice, capability, or requests." },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "What ability does the modal verb 'can/cannot' express?", "options": ["Permission", "Possibility", "Ability/inability", "Obligation"], "correctAnswer": "Ability/inability" },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'may/may not' as a modal verb?", "options": ["Ability", "Obligation", "Permission", "Suggestion"], "correctAnswer": "Permission" },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "What does the modal verb 'might' indicate?", "options": ["Request", "Possibility", "Advice", "Prohibition"], "correctAnswer": "Possibility" },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "Which modal verb is used to express a request?", "options": ["Must", "Might", "Would", "Shall"], "correctAnswer": "Would" },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "What does 'should' suggest as a modal verb?", "options": ["Permission", "Obligation", "Suggestion/advice", "Prohibition"], "correctAnswer": "Suggestion/advice" },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "What does 'Must, need to, have' express as modal verbs?", "options": ["Permission", "Suggestion", "Obligation", "Request"], "correctAnswer": "Obligation" },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "What does 'would, will' express when used for invitations/offers?", "options": ["Ability", "Prohibition", "To offer to do things for people or to invite them to do something.", "Request"], "correctAnswer": "To offer to do things for people or to invite them to do something." },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "What does 'mustn't, can't' express as modal verbs?", "options": ["Permission", "Suggestion", "Prohibition (not allowed)", "Obligation"], "correctAnswer": "Prohibition (not allowed)" },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "What is the function of 'Conjunctions and Transitional Devices' as used for reason in Unit 7?", "options": ["To add information.", "To show sequence.", "Used for reason.", "To compare ideas."], "correctAnswer": "Used for reason." },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "Which transitional device for reason means 'I don't like to play with dolls because it is so childish'?", "options": ["So", "For", "Because", "Therefore"], "correctAnswer": "Because" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "Complete the sentence: 'I am not coming to school today ______ kindly grant me leave of absence.'", "options": ["Because", "For", "So", "With this purpose"], "correctAnswer": "So" },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "What is an 'Adjectival Phrase'?", "options": ["A group of words with a subject and a verb.", "A group of words that functions as a verb.", "A group of words comprising of an adjective.", "A group of words that expresses time."], "correctAnswer": "A group of words comprising of an adjective." },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "In the sentence 'The girl in the red shirt is my best friend,' what type of phrase is 'red shirt'?", "options": ["Noun phrase", "Adverb phrase", "Prepositional phrase", "Adjectival phrase"], "correctAnswer": "Adjectival phrase" },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "What is the structure for the affirmative form of the Past Perfect Tense?", "options": ["Subject + has/have + Verb (3rd form) + object", "Subject + verb (past form) + object", "Subject + had + past participle form of verb.", "Subject + will + verb (base form) + object"], "correctAnswer": "Subject + had + past participle form of verb." },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "What is the negative structure of the Past Perfect Tense?", "options": ["Subject + did not + verb (base form) + object", "Subject + has/have + not + verb (3rd form) + object", "Subject + had + not + past participle form of verb.", "Subject + will not + verb (base form) + object"], "correctAnswer": "Subject + had + not + past participle form of verb." },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "Complete the sentence in past perfect tense: 'I went home after I _______ my task.'", "options": ["Finish", "Was finishing", "Had completed", "Have finished"], "correctAnswer": "Had completed" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "What is a 'Formal Letter'?", "options": ["A letter written to a friend.", "A professional letter, which is written in formal language, in a prescribed format.", "A letter for personal communication.", "A letter that only contains informal language."], "correctAnswer": "A professional letter, which is written in formal language, in a prescribed format." },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "What is one key point to keep in mind while writing a formal letter?", "options": ["Use slang.", "Use contractions.", "Be clear and concise.", "Use informal greetings."], "correctAnswer": "Be clear and concise." },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "What is recommended regarding the tone in a formal letter?", "options": ["A casual tone.", "A humorous tone.", "A professional tone.", "A sarcastic tone."], "correctAnswer": "A professional tone." },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "What is the instruction for proofreading a formal letter?", "options": ["Only check for spelling.", "Skip this step if in a hurry.", "Proofread the letter before sending it to avoid any spelling or grammatical mistakes.", "Have someone else write it."], "correctAnswer": "Proofread the letter before sending it to avoid any spelling or grammatical mistakes." },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "What type of request is made in the example formal letter on page 72?", "options": ["For a job application", "For a school admission", "For street lights in the locality", "For a community event"], "correctAnswer": "For street lights in the locality" },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "Who is the formal letter addressed to in the example?", "options": ["The Mayor", "The City Council", "The Secretary ABC Society", "The Head of Police"], "correctAnswer": "The Secretary ABC Society" },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "What is the reason stated in the formal letter for the request?", "options": ["Streets are always crowded.", "Many crimes take place here because the streets remain dark. People are afraid of going anywhere at night.", "There are too many cars.", "The electricity bill is too high."], "correctAnswer": "Many crimes take place here because the streets remain dark. People are afraid of going anywhere at night." },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "What is the meaning of the word 'slanted' from the Unit 7 review section?", "options": ["Happy", "Excited", "Gloomy", "Devastated"], "correctAnswer": "Gloomy" },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'unrestrained' in the Unit 7 review?", "options": ["Confined", "Controlled", "Toxic", "Relaxed"], "correctAnswer": "Toxic" },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "What does the word 'toxic' mean as per the review vocabulary?", "options": ["Healthy", "Beneficial", "Poisonous", "Safe"], "correctAnswer": "Poisonous" },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "Which question is NOT asked in the 'Answer the following questions' section of the Unit 7 review?", "options": ["What should we do to avoid corruption?", "What role can we play to avoid overpopulation?", "How was the farmer treated by Mr. Shan?", "Have you ever met any disabled or differently abled person in your life?"], "correctAnswer": "How was the farmer treated by Mr. Shan?" }
  ],
  "Importance of Science & Technology (Science and Technology)": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What is the main theme of Unit 8?", "options": ["Corruption", "Education is my Right", "Overpopulation - A Dilemma", "Importance of Science & Technology"], "correctAnswer": "Importance of Science & Technology" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "What is one of the student learning outcomes for Unit 8 related to vocabulary?", "options": ["To use a dictionary for common words only.", "To use dictionary/thesaurus to: use a thesaurus to create synonyms/antonyms, identify phrases through keywords, understand various abbreviation used in a dictionary.", "To learn only new words.", "To identify only nouns and verbs."], "correctAnswer": "To use dictionary/thesaurus to: use a thesaurus to create synonyms/antonyms, identify phrases through keywords, understand various abbreviation used in a dictionary." },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "What grammar concept related to position, time, movement, and direction is covered in Unit 8?", "options": ["Adverbs", "Conjunctions", "Prepositions", "Articles"], "correctAnswer": "Prepositions" },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "What is the primary focus of the writing skill in Unit 8, as indicated by the options for developing a topic?", "options": ["Writing poems.", "Creating short stories.", "Introduce a topic clearly and group related information in short paragraphs and sections; include formatting (e.g., headings), illustration to convey meaning effectively.", "Summarizing research papers."], "correctAnswer": "Introduce a topic clearly and group related information in short paragraphs and sections; include formatting (e.g., headings), illustration to convey meaning effectively." },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "What images are shown in the 'Pre-reading' section of Unit 8?", "options": ["Pictures of different animals.", "Pictures of natural landscapes.", "Pictures of robots (ASIMO by HONDA).", "Pictures of historical figures."], "correctAnswer": "Pictures of robots (ASIMO by HONDA)." },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "What question is posed in the 'Quick Questions' section related to the pre-reading images in Unit 8?", "options": ["How do machines work?", "Why are machines and robots so important in our lives?", "What is the history of robotics?", "How are robots designed?"], "correctAnswer": "Why are machines and robots so important in our lives?" },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "What is the main idea of the reading passage in Unit 8?", "options": ["The history of technology.", "The challenges of modern science.", "Science and technology have facilitated us in many ways and made our life comfortable.", "The negative impacts of technology."], "correctAnswer": "Science and technology have facilitated us in many ways and made our life comfortable." },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "How has science and technology affected daily life, as mentioned in the text?", "options": ["Made life more complicated.", "Reduced human interaction.", "Our day starts with the ticking of the alarm and ends with switching off the lights.", "Increased manual labor."], "correctAnswer": "Our day starts with the ticking of the alarm and ends with switching off the lights." },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "What is the impact of modern and advanced inventions on our work?", "options": ["They make work harder.", "They are only for entertainment.", "Our work is done by different machines which can wash and press our clothes, prepare our meals, and do the dishes etc.", "They cause more pollution."], "correctAnswer": "Our work is done by different machines which can wash and press our clothes, prepare our meals, and do the dishes etc." },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "How has transportation changed due to science and technology?", "options": ["It has become slower and more difficult.", "It has become more expensive.", "Transportation has become easier and faster. Now we can quickly reach our destination within a few minutes, or a few hours.", "It has led to more accidents."], "correctAnswer": "Transportation has become easier and faster. Now we can quickly reach our destination within a few minutes, or a few hours." },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "What is the role of technology in communication?", "options": ["It has made communication impossible.", "Technology helps us to communicate with other people around the world.", "It only allows for written communication.", "It is limited to local communication."], "correctAnswer": "Technology helps us to communicate with other people around the world." },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "How has technology affected the field of education?", "options": ["Students attend classes less frequently.", "Students are getting an education sitting at home. Students are facilitated with smart classes, multimedia devices, e-libraries, e-books, etc.", "Education has become more expensive.", "Teachers are no longer needed."], "correctAnswer": "Students are getting an education sitting at home. Students are facilitated with smart classes, multimedia devices, e-libraries, e-books, etc." },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "What recent global event is mentioned where technology played a vital role?", "options": ["A major earthquake", "A global economic crisis", "The pandemic of Covid-19", "A political revolution"], "correctAnswer": "The pandemic of Covid-19" },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "How did technology help during the Covid-19 pandemic?", "options": ["It created new viruses.", "It made travel impossible.", "Technology became a life saviour for many people. The whole world was transformed to the smart world.", "It increased social isolation."], "correctAnswer": "Technology became a life saviour for many people. The whole world was transformed to the smart world." },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "What contribution has science and technology made to food security?", "options": ["It has decreased food production.", "It has made food unhealthy.", "Science gave us the knowledge about healthy and oil free food and technology gifted us with microwaves and steam-cookers to provide us calories free meal.", "It only provides canned foods."], "correctAnswer": "Science gave us the knowledge about healthy and oil free food and technology gifted us with microwaves and steam-cookers to provide us calories free meal." },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "What kind of medical devices are mentioned that help doctors and patients?", "options": ["Only basic thermometers.", "Traditional herbal remedies.", "Multiple medical devices like X-rays, scan machines, operation devices, pacemakers, and exercise equipment.", "Simple bandages."], "correctAnswer": "Multiple medical devices like X-rays, scan machines, operation devices, pacemakers, and exercise equipment." },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "What has technology changed in the field of health tips?", "options": ["Made them more complicated.", "Now a days online medical facilities have also changed the world. Online health tips, medical assistance, and numerous health apps are the blessings of science and technology.", "Removed the need for doctors.", "Increased health problems."], "correctAnswer": "Now a days online medical facilities have also changed the world. Online health tips, medical assistance, and numerous health apps are the blessings of science and technology." },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "What impact has science had on human survival and space exploration?", "options": ["It has limited our understanding of space.", "Our planet has become overpopulated and scientists are discovering new planets for humans’ survival. They have marked their presence on Mars and are trying to reach other planets too.", "It has made space travel impossible.", "It has only focused on Earth's problems."], "correctAnswer": "Our planet has become overpopulated and scientists are discovering new planets for humans’ survival. They have marked their presence on Mars and are trying to reach other planets too." },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'essential' in the vocabulary list of Unit 8?", "options": ["Unimportant", "Extra", "Important", "Optional"], "correctAnswer": "Important" },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "What does 'luxurious' mean in the context of Unit 8's vocabulary?", "options": ["Basic", "Cheap", "Comfortable", "Difficult"], "correctAnswer": "Comfortable" },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'transformed'?", "options": ["Stagnated", "Remained the same", "Changed", "Decreased"], "correctAnswer": "Changed" },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "What does 'innovation' mean?", "options": ["Old methods", "Traditional practices", "Invention", "Stagnation"], "correctAnswer": "Invention" },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "What is 'Denotative Meaning' in vocabulary?", "options": ["A word's feelings or ideas associated with it.", "A word's denotation is its literal meaning- that is, the definition you find in a dictionary.", "A word's figurative meaning.", "A word's hidden meaning."], "correctAnswer": "A word's denotation is its literal meaning- that is, the definition you find in a dictionary." },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "What are 'Connotative Meanings'?", "options": ["The literal definition of a word.", "A word's connotation is the feelings or ideas associated with a word.", "The dictionary meaning.", "The grammatical function of a word."], "correctAnswer": "A word's connotation is the feelings or ideas associated with a word." },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "In the example, what is the denotation of 'blue' when describing a shirt?", "options": ["Sadness", "Feeling down", "A color", "Calmness"], "correctAnswer": "A color" },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "What is the connotation of 'blue' when referring to a dog?", "options": ["Its physical color.", "Used as a feeling of sadness.", "A bright and happy feeling.", "A neutral feeling."], "correctAnswer": "Used as a feeling of sadness." },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "What is the denotation of 'cool' when referring to temperature?", "options": ["Stylish", "Calm", "Low temperature", "Exciting"], "correctAnswer": "Low temperature" },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "What is the connotation of 'cool' when describing a person?", "options": ["Having a low body temperature.", "Used as stylish.", "Feeling sad.", "Feeling angry."], "correctAnswer": "Used as stylish." },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "How many types of sentences are discussed in Unit 8?", "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four", "Five"], "correctAnswer": "Four" },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "What type of sentence states or expresses a general thing, from very important to minor detail?", "options": ["Exclamatory Sentence", "Interrogative Sentence", "Imperative Sentence", "Declarative Sentence"], "correctAnswer": "Declarative Sentence" },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "What type of sentence expresses strong emotion and ends with an exclamation mark '!'?", "options": ["Declarative Sentence", "Interrogative Sentence", "Exclamatory Sentence", "Imperative Sentence"], "correctAnswer": "Exclamatory Sentence" },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "What does an 'Interrogative Sentence' do?", "options": ["Expresses a strong emotion.", "Gives a command.", "Asks a question.", "Makes a statement."], "correctAnswer": "Asks a question." },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "What kind of sentence asks a question and often begins with an interrogative pronoun (i.e., when, where, which, how etc.) and ends with a question mark (?)?", "options": ["Declarative sentence", "Exclamatory sentence", "Interrogative sentence", "Imperative sentence"], "correctAnswer": "Interrogative sentence" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "What is the purpose of an 'Imperative Sentence'?", "options": ["To ask a question.", "To express strong emotion.", "To make a statement.", "To express a direct command, request, invitations, warning, or instruction."], "correctAnswer": "To express a direct command, request, invitations, warning, or instruction." },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "Which of the following is an example of an imperative sentence?", "options": ["He is eating apples.", "Robert was a good king.", "Please print me a copy of this workbook.", "The sky is blue."], "correctAnswer": "Please print me a copy of this workbook." },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "Which type of sentence is 'The boy put his books and pencils on the table'?", "options": ["Interrogative", "Exclamatory", "Imperative", "Declarative"], "correctAnswer": "Declarative" },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "What type of sentence is 'How are you feeling today?'", "options": ["Declarative", "Exclamatory", "Imperative", "Interrogative"], "correctAnswer": "Interrogative" },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "What type of sentence is 'Wow! The Taj Mahal is so beautiful.'?", "options": ["Declarative", "Interrogative", "Imperative", "Exclamatory"], "correctAnswer": "Exclamatory" },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "What type of sentence is 'Please help me to do this work.'?", "options": ["Declarative", "Interrogative", "Exclamatory", "Imperative"], "correctAnswer": "Imperative" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "What is a 'Speech bubble' in the context of writing skills?", "options": ["A type of cartoon character.", "A round shape next to the head of a character in a cartoon. The character's words or thoughts are written in it.", "A dialogue written in paragraphs.", "A method for outlining stories."], "correctAnswer": "A round shape next to the head of a character in a cartoon. The character's words or thoughts are written in it." },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "What is the National bird of the Philippines, as mentioned in the punctuation exercise?", "options": ["Golden eagle", "Black eagle", "White bellied eagle", "Philippine eagle"], "correctAnswer": "Philippine eagle" },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "How many rare bird species are known in the Philippines according to the text?", "options": ["Five", "Ten", "Over twenty", "Fifteen"], "correctAnswer": "Over twenty" },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "What is the estimated population of the Philippine eagle?", "options": ["Between 100 and 200", "Between 300 and 400", "Between 600 and 650", "Over 1000"], "correctAnswer": "Between 600 and 650" },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "Which learning outcome in Unit 8 focuses on presenting an argument and viewpoint?", "options": ["Distinguish and write four types of sentences.", "Use dictionary/thesaurus to.", "Explain functions of different conjunctions.", "Present an argument and viewpoint with clarity of purpose and a convincing manner."], "correctAnswer": "Present an argument and viewpoint with clarity of purpose and a convincing manner." },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "What is mentioned as a non-print source for reading and viewing in Unit 8?", "options": ["Journal articles", "Novels", "Information reports and texts (e.g., reports, fact sheets)", "Poetry"], "correctAnswer": "Information reports and texts (e.g., reports, fact sheets)" },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "What type of information should be included when developing a topic in writing, according to the learning outcomes?", "options": ["Only personal opinions.", "Only broad statements.", "Facts, definitions, concrete details, quotations, or other information and examples related to the topic.", "Only humorous anecdotes."], "correctAnswer": "Facts, definitions, concrete details, quotations, or other information and examples related to the topic." },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "What is the purpose of 'linking ideas within categories of information' as a writing skill in Unit 8?", "options": ["To make the text shorter.", "To confuse the reader.", "To explain, for example, because.", "To add irrelevant information."], "correctAnswer": "To explain, for example, because." },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "What does 'Adverb Phrases' refer to in the grammar section of Unit 8?", "options": ["A group of words with a subject and a verb.", "A group of words comprising of an adverb.", "A phrase that describes a noun.", "A phrase that functions as a verb."], "correctAnswer": "A group of words comprising of an adverb." },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "What is the rule for 'Apostrophe with singular noun'?", "options": ["Add 's at the end of the word for plural nouns.", "To indicate possession with a singular noun, add 's at the end of the word.", "To form contractions.", "To indicate plural forms."], "correctAnswer": "To indicate possession with a singular noun, add 's at the end of the word." },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "What is the final step in writing an essay on 'Environmental Pollution' according to the mind map on page 83?", "options": ["List causes.", "List solutions.", "List effects.", "Give a concluding statement related to the explanation presented."], "correctAnswer": "Give a concluding statement related to the explanation presented." }
  ],
  "Overpopulation - a Dilemma (Population Education)": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What is the main topic of Unit 9?", "options": ["Environmental Pollution", "Population Education", "Importance of Science & Technology", "Patriotism / National Pride"], "correctAnswer": "Population Education" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "What is one of the student learning outcomes for Unit 9 related to communication?", "options": ["Write informal letters", "Explain different conjunctions", "Develop conversation for clarity and to engage a listener", "Practice note-taking"], "correctAnswer": "Develop conversation for clarity and to engage a listener" },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "According to the 'Pre-reading' section, what is the picture about?", "options": ["Saving electricity", "Planting trees", "Save water", "Reducing pollution"], "correctAnswer": "Save water" },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "In the reading text, what was the weather like on the hot summer night Daniel was lying down?", "options": ["Sunny and clear", "Dusty and cloudy", "Rainy and windy", "Foggy and cold"], "correctAnswer": "Dusty and cloudy" },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "What was Daniel's grandfather's profession before he passed away?", "options": ["A farmer", "A teacher", "A doctor", "Not mentioned in the text"], "correctAnswer": "Not mentioned in the text" },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "How did Daniel's grandfather describe the city they lived in when he was young?", "options": ["It had many tall buildings.", "It was a small village.", "It had not been so densely populated.", "It was full of factories."], "correctAnswer": "It had not been so densely populated." },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "What kind of houses were there previously in Daniel's area according to the text?", "options": ["High-rise apartments", "Commercial buildings", "Only a few houses", "Many bungalows"], "correctAnswer": "Only a few houses" },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "What is mentioned as a consequence of the border of their city having extended due to human inhabitation?", "options": ["Improved infrastructure", "More green spaces", "The explosion of population had created a lot of problems", "Better public transport"], "correctAnswer": "The explosion of population had created a lot of problems" },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "What did Daniel's grandfather ask when Daniel said 'How can population be a problem?'", "options": ["'What do you mean?'", "'Are you not educated?'", "'Why are you in confusion?'", "'Have you not read the news?'"], "correctAnswer": "'Are you not educated?'" },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "According to the text, what is the main reason why humans are suffering more in cities?", "options": ["Lack of entertainment", "Limited job opportunities", "They are not developed enough to cater to the needs of more people.", "Poor governance"], "correctAnswer": "They are not developed enough to cater to the needs of more people." },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "Overpopulation is described as a common observation in which type of nations?", "options": ["Highly developed nations", "Underdeveloped nations", "Island nations", "Nations with small populations"], "correctAnswer": "Underdeveloped nations" },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "What is one major consequence of overpopulation mentioned in the text?", "options": ["Increased economic growth", "Abundance of natural resources", "Unrestricted consumption and unrestrained demand for natural resources", "Improved quality of life"], "correctAnswer": "Unrestricted consumption and unrestrained demand for natural resources" },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "What contributes to the 'unsustainable population growth' according to the text?", "options": ["Renewable energy sources", "Efficient resource management", "The reason behind food and water shortage, climate change, and intergenerational poverty", "Global cooperation"], "correctAnswer": "The reason behind food and water shortage, climate change, and intergenerational poverty" },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "What does 'toxic' mean as per the vocabulary list?", "options": ["Sweet", "Poisonous", "Healthy", "Clear"], "correctAnswer": "Poisonous" },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'clustered' in the context of the reading?", "options": ["Separated", "Scattered", "Grouped", "Isolated"], "correctAnswer": "Grouped" },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "What does 'unrestrained' mean according to the vocabulary list?", "options": ["Limited", "Controlled", "Uncontrolled", "Restrained"], "correctAnswer": "Uncontrolled" },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'intergenerational'?", "options": ["Within one generation", "Between different countries", "Involving several generations", "Concerning a single family"], "correctAnswer": "Involving several generations" },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "What is the antonym of 'happy' as given in the example?", "options": ["Joyful", "Cheerful", "Sad", "Glad"], "correctAnswer": "Sad" },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "Which word is an antonym for 'accomplish'?", "options": ["Achieve", "Attain", "Fail", "Complete"], "correctAnswer": "Fail" },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "What is an antonym for 'accord'?", "options": ["Agree", "Allow", "Dissent", "Assent"], "correctAnswer": "Dissent" },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "What is an antonym for 'diminish'?", "options": ["Reduce", "Decrease", "Increase", "Shrink"], "correctAnswer": "Increase" },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "What does the abbreviation 'Memo' stand for?", "options": ["Memory", "Memorandum", "Memorial", "Mentor"], "correctAnswer": "Memorandum" },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "What does 'AM' stand for?", "options": ["After Midnight", "Around Morning", "Ante Meridian (any time before midday)", "Afternoon Mark"], "correctAnswer": "Ante Meridian (any time before midday)" },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "What does 'AD' stand for?", "options": ["After Death", "Anno Domini", "Active Duty", "Annual Date"], "correctAnswer": "Anno Domini" },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "What does 'BC' stand for?", "options": ["Before Christ", "Before Common", "Basic Code", "Bright Century"], "correctAnswer": "Before Christ" },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "Which abbreviation is used for 'et cetera'?", "options": ["Excl.", "Etc.", "E.g.", "Est."], "correctAnswer": "Etc." },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "What does 'RSVP' stand for?", "options": ["Respond Soon Very Promptly", "Répondez S'il Vous Plaît (please respond)", "Request Special Verification Process", "Ready Steady Vote Please"], "correctAnswer": "Répondez S'il Vous Plaît (please respond)" },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "Which preposition of position is used to indicate something below or underneath?", "options": ["On", "Above", "Under", "Beside"], "correctAnswer": "Under" },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "In the sentence 'My paper is beneath the piles of copies,' what type of preposition is 'beneath'?", "options": ["Preposition of time", "Preposition of movement", "Preposition of position", "Preposition of direction"], "correctAnswer": "Preposition of position" },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "What type of preposition is used to discuss a specific time period, such as a date on the calendar?", "options": ["Preposition of position", "Preposition of movement", "Preposition of time", "Preposition of direction"], "correctAnswer": "Preposition of time" },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "In the example, 'The fox jumped over the lazy dog,' what type of preposition is 'over'?", "options": ["Preposition of position", "Preposition of time", "Preposition of movement and direction", "Preposition of purpose"], "correctAnswer": "Preposition of movement and direction" },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "Which of the following is a conjunction and transitional device used for 'reason'?", "options": ["In order to", "With this purpose", "Given that", "Because"], "correctAnswer": "Because" },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "What does 'so that' indicate as a transitional device?", "options": ["Cause", "Purpose", "Contrast", "Addition"], "correctAnswer": "Purpose" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "Which conjunction and transitional device is used to give a choice between two of the same part of speech?", "options": ["And", "So", "Either...or", "Because"], "correctAnswer": "Either...or" },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "What does 'neither...nor' indicate in a sentence?", "options": ["Choice", "Negative choice", "Addition", "Contrast"], "correctAnswer": "Negative choice" },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "An adverbial phrase refers to a group of words comprising of an _______.", "options": ["Noun", "Verb", "Adjective", "Adverb"], "correctAnswer": "Adverb" },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "Which of the following is an example of an adverbial phrase of time?", "options": ["By hook or by crook", "Down the road", "As soon as possible", "Like an expert"], "correctAnswer": "As soon as possible" },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "What do apostrophes indicate for singular nouns?", "options": ["Plural form", "Something belongs to something or someone else", "An action", "A descriptive quality"], "correctAnswer": "Something belongs to something or someone else" },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "For a singular noun ending in 's', how is possession indicated with an apostrophe?", "options": ["Add 's'", "Add 's' at the end of the word", "Add s'", "No apostrophe needed"], "correctAnswer": "Add 's' at the end of the word" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "How is possession indicated for plural nouns ending in 's'?", "options": ["Add 's'", "Add an apostrophe after the final letter if it is an s or by adding 's' if the final letter is not an s.", "Add s's", "Add 's' before the s"], "correctAnswer": "Add an apostrophe after the final letter if it is an s or by adding 's' if the final letter is not an s." },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "What is the purpose of an apostrophe in a plural noun that does not end in 's'?", "options": ["To indicate a verb", "To show a contraction", "To indicate possession by adding 's'", "To separate words"], "correctAnswer": "To indicate possession by adding 's'" },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "What are the two main sections of the 'Environmental Pollution' mind map?", "options": ["Problems and Solutions", "Causes and Effects", "Local and Global", "Air and Water"], "correctAnswer": "Causes and Effects" },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "Which of the following is a cause of 'Air Pollution' listed in the mind map?", "options": ["Global warming", "Lung problems", "Use less transportation", "Reduce forest fires"], "correctAnswer": "Reduce forest fires" },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "What is a listed solution to 'Environmental Pollution'?", "options": ["Acid rain", "Smog", "Avoid the usage of refrigerators and ACs", "Depletion of ozone layer"], "correctAnswer": "Avoid the usage of refrigerators and ACs" },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "Which of the following is an 'effect' of 'Environmental Pollution' according to the mind map?", "options": ["No plastic", "Reduce forest fires and smoking", "Irritation of eyes, nose and throat", "Use less transportation"], "correctAnswer": "Irritation of eyes, nose and throat" },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "What can be reduced to mitigate 'increased respiratory problems' caused by pollution?", "options": ["Acid rain", "Energy levels", "Global warming", "Ozone layer depletion"], "correctAnswer": "Ozone layer depletion" },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'gloomy' from the review exercise?", "options": ["Happy", "Excited", "Sad", "Bright"], "correctAnswer": "Sad" },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'slanted' in the review section?", "options": ["Upright", "Oblique", "Straight", "Level"], "correctAnswer": "Oblique" },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "What is a 'bribery'?", "options": ["Honesty", "Generosity", "The act of giving or taking bribes", "Fairness"], "correctAnswer": "The act of giving or taking bribes" },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'toxic' in the review exercise?", "options": ["Edible", "Harmless", "Poisonous", "Beneficial"], "correctAnswer": "Poisonous" }
  ],
  "Education is my Right (Gender Equality and Equity)": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What is the main theme of Unit 10?", "options": ["Overpopulation - a Dilemma", "A Poem by a Soldier", "Gender Equality and Equity", "Importance of Science & Technology"], "correctAnswer": "Gender Equality and Equity" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "What is one of the student learning outcomes for Unit 10 related to text interaction?", "options": ["Read and view a variety of reading- age-appropriate and high-interest books and texts", "Write a formal letter", "Conduct debates on given topics", "Discuss rules and regulations"], "correctAnswer": "Read and view a variety of reading- age-appropriate and high-interest books and texts" },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "What is mentioned as a specific skill students will learn regarding figurative language in Unit 10?", "options": ["Identifying onomatopoeia only", "Understand and utilize figurative language: similes, metaphors, personification, and hyperbole", "Creating new metaphors", "Analyzing poetic meter"], "correctAnswer": "Understand and utilize figurative language: similes, metaphors, personification, and hyperbole" },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "What was Mr. Akbar's initial reaction when Ameena's parents asked him to help their daughter get an education?", "options": ["He immediately agreed.", "He was hesitant.", "He did not lose hope and went to encourage villagers.", "He asked for money."], "correctAnswer": "He did not lose hope and went to encourage villagers." },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "What was Ameena's main problem concerning education?", "options": ["She was not intelligent enough.", "Her parents refused to send her.", "She faced many challenges to have access to education, including poverty.", "There were no schools nearby."], "correctAnswer": "She faced many challenges to have access to education, including poverty." },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "How did Mr. Akbar support Ameena's education initially?", "options": ["He paid all her fees.", "He arranged a meeting with other villagers to get support.", "He taught her at home.", "He bought her all books."], "correctAnswer": "He arranged a meeting with other villagers to get support." },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "What did Ameena promise her parents after Mr. Akbar's intervention?", "options": ["To study only at home", "To teach them too, despite challenges.", "To move to another village", "To join a different school"], "correctAnswer": "To teach them too, despite challenges." },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "Why did Ameena's parents initially refuse to send their daughters to school?", "options": ["They thought it was unnecessary.", "They were awkward for her, but willing to do it for the sake of her education.", "They wanted them to work.", "The school was too far."], "correctAnswer": "They were awkward for her, but willing to do it for the sake of her education." },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "What happened to the snakebite victim that Ameena and Mr. Akbar encountered?", "options": ["They took him to the nearest hospital.", "A ward boy was attending him, and Ameena rushed to help.", "They called for an ambulance.", "The text does not specify."], "correctAnswer": "A ward boy was attending him, and Ameena rushed to help." },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "How did Ameena contribute to helping the snakebite victim?", "options": ["She ran to get a doctor.", "She gave him medicine.", "She carefully dressed the wound and talked to the attendant.", "She massaged his leg."], "correctAnswer": "She carefully dressed the wound and talked to the attendant." },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "Why was Ameena happy in her heart at the end of the story?", "options": ["She got good grades.", "Mr. Akbar appreciated her efforts and the landlord promised her a reward.", "She found a new school.", "Her family became rich."], "correctAnswer": "Mr. Akbar appreciated her efforts and the landlord promised her a reward." },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "What does 'smash' mean in the context of the reading?", "options": ["Build", "Break (something) into pieces", "Join", "Repair"], "correctAnswer": "Break (something) into pieces" },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'barren'?", "options": ["Fertile", "Productive", "(of land) too poor to produce much/unproductive", "Lush"], "correctAnswer": "(of land) too poor to produce much/unproductive" },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "What does 'encounter' mean?", "options": ["Avoid", "Unexpectedly be faced with or experience (something hostile or difficult)", "Ignore", "Escape"], "correctAnswer": "Unexpectedly be faced with or experience (something hostile or difficult)" },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "What is the definition of 'awkward'?", "options": ["Easy", "Graceful", "Causing difficulty; hard to do or deal with", "Simple"], "correctAnswer": "Causing difficulty; hard to do or deal with" },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "What does 'inequality' refer to?", "options": ["Similarity", "Difference in size, degree, circumstances, etc.; lack of equality", "Fairness", "Balance"], "correctAnswer": "Difference in size, degree, circumstances, etc.; lack of equality" },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "What is an 'opportunity'?", "options": ["A hindrance", "A challenge", "A time or set of circumstances that makes it possible to do something", "A problem"], "correctAnswer": "A time or set of circumstances that makes it possible to do something" },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "What is the school building described as in the story?", "options": ["New and modern", "Old and dilapidated", "Small and clean", "Spacious and well-maintained"], "correctAnswer": "Old and dilapidated" },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "According to the story, what were the major issues in education in Pakistan?", "options": ["Lack of qualified teachers", "Expensive tuition fees", "Poverty, parents' refusal to send daughters, lack of awareness", "Shortage of textbooks"], "correctAnswer": "Poverty, parents' refusal to send daughters, lack of awareness" },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "What is 'Metaphor'?", "options": ["A comparison using 'like' or 'as'", "Giving human qualities to non-human objects", "An exaggeration", "The direct comparison of two unlikely things"], "correctAnswer": "The direct comparison of two unlikely things" },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "Which example illustrates a metaphor?", "options": ["Raining cats and dogs", "The leaves danced on the wind", "I could eat a whole cow", "Buzzard with a loud clang/bang"], "correctAnswer": "Raining cats and dogs" },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "What is 'Personification'?", "options": ["A direct comparison", "Giving human qualities to non-human objects", "An exaggeration", "Words that imitate sounds"], "correctAnswer": "Giving human qualities to non-human objects" },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "Which example shows personification?", "options": ["She is as cold as ice.", "The leaves danced on the wind.", "I am so strong I can lift over two tons!", "Buzzard with a loud clang/bang."], "correctAnswer": "The leaves danced on the wind." },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "What is 'Hyperbole'?", "options": ["A comparison of unlike things", "Giving human qualities", "Words that imitate sounds", "An exaggerated phrase"], "correctAnswer": "An exaggerated phrase" },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "Which example is an instance of hyperbole?", "options": ["He has a heart of gold.", "The streets are calling me.", "I could eat a whole cow.", "The door shut with a loud clang/bang."], "correctAnswer": "I could eat a whole cow." },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "What is 'Onomatopoeia'?", "options": ["A comparison of unlike things", "Giving human qualities", "An exaggeration", "Words that imitate sounds"], "correctAnswer": "Words that imitate sounds" },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "Which example demonstrates onomatopoeia?", "options": ["She is as cold as ice.", "The leaves danced on the wind.", "I am so strong I can lift over two tons!", "The door shut with a loud clang/bang."], "correctAnswer": "The door shut with a loud clang/bang." },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "Which type of figurative language is 'My mother loves me a lot. She says, 'You are my sunshine''?", "options": ["Simile", "Metaphor", "Personification", "Hyperbole"], "correctAnswer": "Metaphor" },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "Which type of figurative language is 'I am so strong I can lift over two tons!'?", "options": ["Simile", "Metaphor", "Personification", "Hyperbole"], "correctAnswer": "Hyperbole" },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "What connects two independent clauses in a compound sentence?", "options": ["A subordinating conjunction", "A coordinating conjunction", "A relative pronoun", "An adverbial phrase"], "correctAnswer": "A coordinating conjunction" },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "Which of the following is NOT a coordinating conjunction mentioned?", "options": ["And", "But", "Although", "Or"], "correctAnswer": "Although" },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "What joins one or more dependent clauses to an independent clause in a complex sentence?", "options": ["Coordinating conjunction", "Subordinating conjunction", "Preposition", "Adverb"], "correctAnswer": "Subordinating conjunction" },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "Which of the following is a subordinating conjunction mentioned in the sources?", "options": ["And", "Or", "Although", "Nor"], "correctAnswer": "Although" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "A dependent clause cannot do what by itself?", "options": ["Stand by itself", "Contain a subject", "Contain a verb", "Be part of a complex sentence"], "correctAnswer": "Stand by itself" },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "What is the writing skill focused on in Unit 10?", "options": ["Narrative paragraph", "Formal letter", "Biography", "Essay writing"], "correctAnswer": "Biography" },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "What is the first step in planning a biography as per the mind map?", "options": ["Career", "Family", "Qualities", "Childhood"], "correctAnswer": "Childhood" },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "What information is included in the 'Place of Birth' section of a biography?", "options": ["Hobbies", "Education", "Physical description", "Marital status"], "correctAnswer": "Education" },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "The 'Age and date of death' section of a biography includes what information?", "options": ["Financial status", "Achievements", "Their traits and family (habits, etc.)", "Future plans"], "correctAnswer": "Their traits and family (habits, etc.)" },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "What type of detail should be used for arranging a biography?", "options": ["Alphabetical order", "Random order", "Chronological/sequential order", "By importance"], "correctAnswer": "Chronological/sequential order" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "What kind of words should be used in a biography according to the checklist?", "options": ["Simple words only", "Technical jargon", "Specific words, vivid verbs, modifiers, etc.", "Passive voice words"], "correctAnswer": "Specific words, vivid verbs, modifiers, etc." },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "What should be added to ensure the biography is well-supported?", "options": ["Personal opinions", "Adequate supporting details", "Unrelated facts", "Exaggerations"], "correctAnswer": "Adequate supporting details" },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "What pronoun should be used appropriately in a biography?", "options": ["First person", "Second person", "Antecedent agreement", "Only proper nouns"], "correctAnswer": "Antecedent agreement" },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "What must be used to ensure coherence in a biography?", "options": ["Idioms", "Figures of speech", "Appropriate transitional devices", "Technical terms"], "correctAnswer": "Appropriate transitional devices" },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'luxurious' in the review section?", "options": ["Simple", "Cheap", "Comfortable and expensive", "Small"], "correctAnswer": "Comfortable and expensive" },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'ease' in the review section?", "options": ["Difficulty", "Stress", "Comfort", "Problem"], "correctAnswer": "Comfort" },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "What does 'vigilant' mean in the review section?", "options": ["Careless", "Inattentive", "Alert", "Sleepy"], "correctAnswer": "Alert" },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "How many types of figurative language are reviewed in this unit?", "options": ["Three", "Four", "Five", "Two"], "correctAnswer": "Five" },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "What is the definition of 'bow' as given in the review vocabulary?", "options": ["A weapon", "To take a seat", "To bend the head or upper part of the body as a sign of respect or greeting", "A type of knot"], "correctAnswer": "To bend the head or upper part of the body as a sign of respect or greeting" },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "What does 'war zone' refer to?", "options": ["A peaceful area", "A recreational area", "An area of armed conflict", "A protected sanctuary"], "correctAnswer": "An area of armed conflict" },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "What is 'imbibe'?", "options": ["To give out", "To refuse", "To absorb", "To reject"], "correctAnswer": "To absorb" }
  ],
  "A Poem by a Soldier (Patriotism / National Pride)": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What is the theme of Unit 11?", "options": ["Good Citizen", "Harmony in Society", "Patriotism / National Pride", "Corruption"], "correctAnswer": "Patriotism / National Pride" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "What is one of the student learning outcomes for Unit 11 related to text comprehension?", "options": ["Explain idioms", "Identify transitive verbs", "Read and view a variety of age-appropriate and high-interest books and texts", "Write an autobiography"], "correctAnswer": "Read and view a variety of age-appropriate and high-interest books and texts" },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "What specific grammar skill is focused on in Unit 11?", "options": ["Adjectives", "Prepositions", "Change of tense in indirect speech", "Conditional sentences"], "correctAnswer": "Change of tense in indirect speech" },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "Who was Rashid Minhas Shaheed?", "options": ["A doctor", "A teacher", "A pilot in the Pakistan Air Force", "A politician"], "correctAnswer": "A pilot in the Pakistan Air Force" },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "What award did Rashid Minhas receive?", "options": ["Nishan-e-Imtiaz", "Nishan-e-Haider", "Sitara-e-Jurat", "Hilal-e-Jurrat"], "correctAnswer": "Nishan-e-Haider" },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "When was Rashid Minhas born?", "options": ["January 17, 1950", "February 17, 1951", "March 17, 1952", "April 17, 1953"], "correctAnswer": "February 17, 1951" },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "Where did Rashid Minhas receive his early education?", "options": ["Lahore", "Karachi", "Rawalpindi", "Islamabad"], "correctAnswer": "Karachi" },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "What did Rashid Minhas do after graduating from St Mary's Cambridge School?", "options": ["Joined the army", "Shifted to Karachi to pursue his keen interest in aviation history and technology", "Became a teacher", "Started his own business"], "correctAnswer": "Shifted to Karachi to pursue his keen interest in aviation history and technology" },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "What was Rashid Minhas's rank at the Pakistan Airforce Academy in Risalpur?", "options": ["Pilot Officer", "Flying Officer", "A flying cadet", "Squadron Leader"], "correctAnswer": "A flying cadet" },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "When did Rashid Minhas graduate as a fighter pilot?", "options": ["1970", "1971", "1972", "1973"], "correctAnswer": "1971" },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "What type of aircraft was Rashid Minhas training on when the incident occurred?", "options": ["F-16", "Mirage", "T-33 jet trainer", "F-7"], "correctAnswer": "T-33 jet trainer" },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "Who was Matiur Rahman?", "options": ["A fellow student", "An Indian fellowmen", "A family friend", "A senior instructor"], "correctAnswer": "An Indian fellowmen" },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "What was Matiur Rahman's intention when he hijacked the plane?", "options": ["To fly to another airbase", "To surrender to the enemy", "To defect and land the plane on Indian airbase", "To perform an aerobatic stunt"], "correctAnswer": "To defect and land the plane on Indian airbase" },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "How did Rashid Minhas prevent the plane from landing on the Indian airbase?", "options": ["He shot Matiur Rahman.", "He managed to regain control and land safely.", "He crashed the plane.", "He parachuted out of the plane."], "correctAnswer": "He crashed the plane." },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "What does the term 'bravery' imply in the context of Rashid Minhas?", "options": ["Cowardice", "Courage", "Fear", "Weakness"], "correctAnswer": "Courage" },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'recovered' in the context of Rashid Minhas's story?", "options": ["Found something lost", "Got back or regained possession of", "Healed from illness", "Became famous"], "correctAnswer": "Got back or regained possession of" },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "What does 'chivalrous' mean?", "options": ["Dishonorable", "Selfish", "Courageous and honorable", "Weak"], "correctAnswer": "Courageous and honorable" },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "What is the literal meaning of a word according to the dictionary?", "options": ["Connotative meaning", "Figurative meaning", "Denotative meaning", "Contextual meaning"], "correctAnswer": "Denotative meaning" },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "What does 'Connotative Meaning' refer to?", "options": ["The dictionary definition", "The feelings or ideas associated with a word", "The phonetic transcription", "The grammatical function"], "correctAnswer": "The feelings or ideas associated with a word" },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "In the example, 'He wore the blue shirt,' what is the denotation of 'blue'?", "options": ["A feeling of sadness", "A stylistic choice", "A color", "A cold temperature"], "correctAnswer": "A color" },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "In the example, 'Bobby was blue after his dog died,' what is the connotation of 'blue'?", "options": ["A color", "Feeling of sadness", "Temperature", "Style"], "correctAnswer": "Feeling of sadness" },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "How many types of sentences are listed?", "options": ["Three", "Four", "Five", "Two"], "correctAnswer": "Four" },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "What type of sentence expresses a statement and generally ends with a period?", "options": ["Interrogative sentence", "Exclamatory sentence", "Imperative sentence", "Declarative sentence"], "correctAnswer": "Declarative sentence" },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "What type of sentence asks a question and ends with a question mark?", "options": ["Declarative sentence", "Exclamatory sentence", "Imperative sentence", "Interrogative sentence"], "correctAnswer": "Interrogative sentence" },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "What type of sentence expresses strong emotion and ends with an exclamation mark?", "options": ["Declarative sentence", "Interrogative sentence", "Imperative sentence", "Exclamatory sentence"], "correctAnswer": "Exclamatory sentence" },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "What type of sentence expresses a direct command, request, invitation, warning, or instruction?", "options": ["Declarative sentence", "Interrogative sentence", "Exclamatory sentence", "Imperative sentence"], "correctAnswer": "Imperative sentence" },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "In direct speech, the words actually spoken must be put between what punctuation marks?", "options": ["Parentheses ()", "Brackets []", "Quotation marks (' ')", "Apostrophes ''"], "correctAnswer": "Quotation marks (' ')" },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "In direct speech, the first word in the quotation marks begins with what?", "options": ["A lowercase letter", "A capital letter", "A number", "An exclamation mark"], "correctAnswer": "A capital letter" },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "When using direct speech for statements, exclamations, questions, or orders, what rule applies?", "options": ["Use only periods", "Only question marks for questions", "The punctuation mark is included inside the quotation marks.", "No punctuation inside quotation marks"], "correctAnswer": "The punctuation mark is included inside the quotation marks." },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "In direct speech, what usually changes from 'I' to 'he, she, they' in indirect speech?", "options": ["Verbs", "Adverbs", "Pronouns", "Conjunctions"], "correctAnswer": "Pronouns" },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "If the reporting verb is in the past tense, what generally happens to the tense in the reported speech?", "options": ["It remains unchanged.", "It changes to the present tense.", "It changes to the corresponding past tense.", "It changes to the future tense."], "correctAnswer": "It changes to the corresponding past tense." },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "If the direct speech is in 'Present Simple Tense,' what does it become in indirect speech?", "options": ["Present perfect tense", "Future simple tense", "Past simple tense", "Present continuous tense"], "correctAnswer": "Past simple tense" },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "If the direct speech is in 'Present Continuous Tense,' what does it become in indirect speech?", "options": ["Present simple tense", "Past continuous tense", "Present perfect continuous tense", "Future continuous tense"], "correctAnswer": "Past continuous tense" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "If the direct speech is in 'Present Perfect Tense,' what does it become in indirect speech?", "options": ["Present simple tense", "Past simple tense", "Past perfect tense", "Past continuous tense"], "correctAnswer": "Past perfect tense" },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "If the direct speech is in 'Present Perfect Continuous Tense,' what does it become in indirect speech?", "options": ["Present simple tense", "Past simple tense", "Present perfect tense", "Past perfect continuous tense"], "correctAnswer": "Past perfect continuous tense" },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "If the direct speech is in 'Past Simple Tense,' what does it become in indirect speech?", "options": ["Past continuous tense", "Past perfect tense", "Present perfect tense", "Future perfect tense"], "correctAnswer": "Past perfect tense" },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "If the direct speech is in 'Past Continuous Tense,' what does it become in indirect speech?", "options": ["Past simple tense", "Past perfect continuous tense", "Present perfect continuous tense", "Future perfect continuous tense"], "correctAnswer": "Past perfect continuous tense" },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "If the direct speech contains 'Future Indefinite Tense' (will), what does it become in indirect speech?", "options": ["Will be", "Would", "Would have", "Will have been"], "correctAnswer": "Would" },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "If the direct speech contains 'Future Continuous Tense' (will be), what does it become in indirect speech?", "options": ["Will be had", "Would be have", "Would be", "Will have been"], "correctAnswer": "Would be" },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "If the direct speech contains 'Future Perfect Tense' (will have), what does it become in indirect speech?", "options": ["Will have been", "Would be", "Would have", "Will be had"], "correctAnswer": "Would have" },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "What is the required length for an essay in this unit?", "options": ["100-200 words", "200-300 words", "350-400 words", "400-500 words"], "correctAnswer": "350-400 words" },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "How many paragraphs should an essay have according to the unit?", "options": ["Two", "At least three", "Five", "As many as needed"], "correctAnswer": "At least three" },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "What are the three main parts of an essay mentioned in the unit?", "options": ["Introduction, body, conclusion", "Topic, details, summary", "Planning, drafting, reviewing", "Beginning, middle, end"], "correctAnswer": "Introduction, body, conclusion" },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "What part of an essay contains the main idea?", "options": ["Concluding paragraph", "Supporting details", "Introductory paragraph", "Main body"], "correctAnswer": "Introductory paragraph" },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "What part of an essay contains supporting details?", "options": ["Introductory paragraph", "Concluding paragraph", "Main body", "Title"], "correctAnswer": "Main body" },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "What part of an essay contains a summary of the essay?", "options": ["Introductory paragraph", "Main body", "Concluding paragraph", "Supporting details"], "correctAnswer": "Concluding paragraph" },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "What is the purpose of the essay writing skill in this unit?", "options": ["To write stories", "To analyze poems", "To compose a full length essay/story", "To write dialogues"], "correctAnswer": "To compose a full length essay/story" },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "What is the essay topic suggested in the unit?", "options": ["My country", "My hero", "'My father is my hero.'", "My favorite soldier"], "correctAnswer": "'My father is my hero.'" },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'sacred' in the review section?", "options": ["Ordinary", "Common", "Holy", "Profane"], "correctAnswer": "Holy" },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "What does 'struggle' mean?", "options": ["Rest", "Ease", "Effort", "Retreat"], "correctAnswer": "Effort" }
  ],
  "Good Citizen (Participatory Citizenship)": [
    { "id": 1, "questionText": "What is the main topic of Unit 12?", "options": ["Education is my Right", "Harmony in Society", "Participatory Citizenship", "Corruption"], "correctAnswer": "Participatory Citizenship" },
    { "id": 2, "questionText": "What is one of the student learning outcomes for Unit 12 related to communication?", "options": ["Explain different conjunctions", "Write a formal letter", "Develop conversation for clarity and to engage a listener", "Practice note-taking"], "correctAnswer": "Develop conversation for clarity and to engage a listener" },
    { "id": 3, "questionText": "What specific grammar skill is focused on in Unit 12?", "options": ["Adjectives and adverbs", "Tenses", "Change of tense in indirect speech", "Pronouns"], "correctAnswer": "Change of tense in indirect speech" },
    { "id": 4, "questionText": "What is the 'Pre-reading' section in Unit 12 about?", "options": ["Road safety rules", "Traffic Rules And Signs", "Driving laws", "Pedestrian safety"], "correctAnswer": "Traffic Rules And Signs" },
    { "id": 5, "questionText": "According to the text, how are Shiza and Tania described?", "options": ["Playful and energetic", "Very responsible and obedient girls", "Intelligent and hardworking", "Quiet and shy"], "correctAnswer": "Very responsible and obedient girls" },
    { "id": 6, "questionText": "What did Shiza and Tania learn from their parents and teachers?", "options": ["How to cook", "How to play sports", "Good citizenship, including duty and responsibility", "How to manage money"], "correctAnswer": "Good citizenship, including duty and responsibility" },
    { "id": 7, "questionText": "What is one aspect of good citizenship that Shiza and Tania believe in?", "options": ["Helping only family members", "Avoiding community work", "To stay loyal and responsible to our society and nation.", "Only focusing on personal achievements."], "correctAnswer": "To stay loyal and responsible to our society and nation." },
    { "id": 8, "questionText": "What did Shiza and Tania decide to do in their society's betterment?", "options": ["Start a business", "Clean their neighborhood and plant some trees", "Organize a festival", "Build a new school"], "correctAnswer": "Clean their neighborhood and plant some trees" },
    { "id": 9, "questionText": "What did Shiza and Tania observe in the street and garden one evening?", "options": ["Children playing", "New buildings being constructed", "Dead plants from pots and the ground", "Street vendors"], "correctAnswer": "Dead plants from pots and the ground" },
    { "id": 10, "questionText": "What did Shiza and Tania and their group do to address the issue of dead plants?", "options": ["Ignored it", "Complained to the authorities", "Worked together to fulfill their responsibility", "Hired gardeners"], "correctAnswer": "Worked together to fulfill their responsibility" },
    { "id": 11, "questionText": "What happened to Shiza's mother when she went to take a shower?", "options": ["The water stopped running.", "She noticed a stranger in the street.", "The lights went out.", "She heard a strange noise."], "correctAnswer": "The water stopped running." },
    { "id": 12, "questionText": "What was Shiza's reaction to seeing the stranger in the street?", "options": ["She went to confront him.", "She ignored him.", "She felt a sixth sense and grew curious.", "She called the police immediately."], "correctAnswer": "She felt a sixth sense and grew curious." },
    { "id": 13, "questionText": "What did Shiza notice about the stranger's movement?", "options": ["He was running.", "He was hiding.", "He looked around suspiciously.", "He was walking normally."], "correctAnswer": "He looked around suspiciously." },
    { "id": 14, "questionText": "What happened when the stranger used his mobile phone?", "options": ["He made a call to his family.", "He dialed a number and then stood outside as if waiting for someone.", "He played a game.", "He took a picture."], "correctAnswer": "He dialed a number and then stood outside as if waiting for someone." },
    { "id": 15, "questionText": "What did Shiza overhear the stranger saying?", "options": ["His name", "His address", "A number and that he had opened the gate for his friends.", "His plans for the day."], "correctAnswer": "A number and that he had opened the gate for his friends." },
    { "id": 16, "questionText": "What was Shiza's immediate action after hearing the stranger?", "options": ["She called her father.", "She ran away.", "She bravely stood there to keep an eye on their next actions.", "She shouted for help."], "correctAnswer": "She bravely stood there to keep an eye on their next actions." },
    { "id": 17, "questionText": "What did Shiza do while observing the stranger?", "options": ["She called the police.", "She took pictures.", "She called the helpline and told them what she had observed.", "She confronted the stranger."], "correctAnswer": "She called the helpline and told them what she had observed." },
    { "id": 18, "questionText": "What was the police's response to Shiza's report?", "options": ["They told her to ignore it.", "They said they would investigate later.", "They arrived promptly and quietly locked the inner door to avoid any danger.", "They asked her to come to the station."], "correctAnswer": "They arrived promptly and quietly locked the inner door to avoid any danger." },
    { "id": 19, "questionText": "What does 'imbibe' mean as per the vocabulary list?", "options": ["To release", "To absorb", "To reject", "To emit"], "correctAnswer": "To absorb" },
    { "id": 20, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'vigilant'?", "options": ["Careless", "Alert", "Sleepy", "Distracted"], "correctAnswer": "Alert" },
    { "id": 21, "questionText": "What does 'engrossed' mean?", "options": ["Disinterested", "Bored", "Attracted", "Annoyed"], "correctAnswer": "Attracted" },
    { "id": 22, "questionText": "What is the meaning of 'astuteness'?", "options": ["Stupidity", "Naivety", "Intelligence", "Ignorance"], "correctAnswer": "Intelligence" },
    { "id": 23, "questionText": "What does 'detect' mean?", "options": ["Hide", "Ignore", "Identify", "Lose"], "correctAnswer": "Identify" },
    { "id": 24, "questionText": "What does 'appreciation' mean?", "options": ["Disapproval", "Criticism", "A fire valuation", "Undervaluing"], "correctAnswer": "A fire valuation" },
    { "id": 25, "questionText": "What did Shiza and Tania learn in school about good citizenship?", "options": ["How to make money.", "How to pass exams.", "Responsible and obedient behavior.", "How to be popular."], "correctAnswer": "Responsible and obedient behavior." },
    { "id": 26, "questionText": "Why were Shiza's and Tania's surroundings clean?", "options": ["Cleaners cleaned it.", "Their parents did it.", "They decided to do it as citizens.", "It was naturally clean."], "correctAnswer": "They decided to do it as citizens." },
    { "id": 27, "questionText": "How did Shiza's curious observation help the community?", "options": ["It made her famous.", "It led to a debate.", "It led to the arrest of criminals and prevention of crime.", "It helped her family."], "correctAnswer": "It led to the arrest of criminals and prevention of crime." },
    { "id": 28, "questionText": "What is 'Onomatopoeia'?", "options": ["A figure of speech showing comparison.", "A figure of speech that exaggerates.", "A figure of speech in which words evoke the actual sound of the thing they refer to or describe.", "A figure of speech that gives human qualities to inanimate objects."], "correctAnswer": "A figure of speech in which words evoke the actual sound of the thing they refer to or describe." },
    { "id": 29, "questionText": "Which of the following is an example of onomatopoeia?", "options": ["Ducks swam quietly.", "Chickens are happy.", "Ducks quacked loudly.", "Lions roared softly."], "correctAnswer": "Ducks quacked loudly." },
    { "id": 30, "questionText": "In the sentence, 'The chickens' vegetables are sizzling in the pan,' which word is an example of onomatopoeia?", "options": ["Vegetables", "Pan", "Sizzling", "Chickens"], "correctAnswer": "Sizzling" },
    { "id": 31, "questionText": "In the sentence, 'Shiza heard a huge roar and she turned around and saw there was a lion in a cage behind her,' which word is an example of onomatopoeia?", "options": ["Huge", "Lion", "Roar", "Cage"], "correctAnswer": "Roar" },
    { "id": 32, "questionText": "What is the writing skill related to Onomatopoeia in Unit 12?", "options": ["Writing a paragraph", "Making it interesting by using onomatopoeia.", "Writing a narrative", "Writing a formal letter"], "correctAnswer": "Making it interesting by using onomatopoeia." },
    { "id": 33, "questionText": "What are the two types of speech discussed in grammar?", "options": ["Formal and informal", "Present and past", "Direct and Indirect Speech", "Reported and active"], "correctAnswer": "Direct and Indirect Speech" },
    { "id": 34, "questionText": "What is one rule for changing Direct Speech into Indirect Speech?", "options": ["Keep commas as they are.", "Remove the comma and the quotation marks.", "Add quotation marks.", "Change all verbs to past tense."], "correctAnswer": "Remove the comma and the quotation marks." },
    { "id": 35, "questionText": "What reporting verb is often used to introduce indirect speech?", "options": ["Said", "Asked", "'that'", "Will"], "correctAnswer": "'that'" },
    { "id": 36, "questionText": "How do pronouns typically change when converting direct to indirect speech?", "options": ["They remain the same.", "They always change to 'he' or 'she'.", "'I' and 'we' into 'he, she, they' and 'me, us' into 'him, her, them'.", "They change to possessive pronouns."], "correctAnswer": "'I' and 'we' into 'he, she, they' and 'me, us' into 'him, her, them'." },
    { "id": 37, "questionText": "If the direct speech is in 'Present Simple Tense,' what rule applies for indirect speech?", "options": ["Use base form of verb.", "Use present participle.", "Use simple past form of verb.", "Use future simple form."], "correctAnswer": "Use simple past form of verb." },
    { "id": 38, "questionText": "'He said, 'I live in the city center'' becomes what in indirect speech?", "options": ["He said that he lives in the city center.", "He said that he lived in the city center.", "He said that I live in the city center.", "He said that he will live in the city center."], "correctAnswer": "He said that he lived in the city center." },
    { "id": 39, "questionText": "'She said, 'She always wears coat'' becomes what in indirect speech?", "options": ["She said that she always wore coat.", "She said that she always wears coat.", "She said that she would always wear coat.", "She said that I always wear coat."], "correctAnswer": "She said that she always wears coat." },
    { "id": 40, "questionText": "'He said, 'his friend gives him a bar of chocolate'' becomes what in indirect speech?", "options": ["He said that his friend gives him a bar of chocolate.", "He said that his friend gave him a bar of chocolate.", "He said that his friend had given him a bar of chocolate.", "He said that his friend will give him a bar of chocolate."], "correctAnswer": "He said that his friend gave him a bar of chocolate." },
    { "id": 41, "questionText": "'Ayesha said, 'I arrive before you'' becomes what in indirect speech?", "options": ["Ayesha said that she arrives before you.", "Ayesha said that she arrived before you.", "Ayesha said that she had arrived before you.", "Ayesha said that she will arrive before you."], "correctAnswer": "Ayesha said that she arrived before you." },
    { "id": 42, "questionText": "'Ayat said, 'She does not play football'' becomes what in indirect speech?", "options": ["Ayat said that she does not play football.", "Ayat said that she did not play football.", "Ayat said that she had not played football.", "Ayat said that she will not play football."], "correctAnswer": "Ayat said that she did not play football." },
    { "id": 43, "questionText": "'The policeman said to the boy, 'where do you live?'' becomes what in indirect speech?", "options": ["The policeman asked the boy where he lives.", "The policeman asked the boy where he lived.", "The policeman asked the boy where did he live.", "The policeman asked the boy where you live."], "correctAnswer": "The policeman asked the boy where he lived." },
    { "id": 44, "questionText": "What punctuation should be used for Ms Maryam's name when writing a paragraph?", "options": ["No capitalization", "Capitalization", "Quotation marks", "Parentheses"], "correctAnswer": "Capitalization" },
    { "id": 45, "questionText": "What is the writing skill taught in Unit 12?", "options": ["Essay writing", "Formal letter writing", "Biography writing", "Narrative writing"], "correctAnswer": "Narrative writing" },
    { "id": 46, "questionText": "What is the first step in planning a narrative paragraph?", "options": ["Drafting", "Reviewing", "Thinking about the topic title of the narrative", "Organizing events"], "correctAnswer": "Thinking about the topic title of the narrative" },
    { "id": 47, "questionText": "What should be identified about the characters in a narrative?", "options": ["Their age", "Their hobbies", "Their characteristics", "Their family"], "correctAnswer": "Their characteristics" },
    { "id": 48, "questionText": "What aspect of the narrative setting should be considered during planning?", "options": ["Time", "Place", "Both time and place (When/where)", "Characters"], "correctAnswer": "Both time and place (When/where)" },
    { "id": 49, "questionText": "What tense should generally be used in narrative writing?", "options": ["Present simple", "Future tense", "Simple past tense", "Present continuous"], "correctAnswer": "Simple past tense" },
    { "id": 50, "questionText": "What is the final step in writing a narrative according to the guidelines?", "options": ["Planning", "Drafting", "Proofreading the final draft to check for any errors and make necessary corrections", "Organizing events in right order"], "correctAnswer": "Proofreading the final draft to check for any errors and make necessary corrections" }
  ],
}

